Joe Rogan podcast check it out The Joe
Rogan Experience Train by day Joe Rogan
podcast by night all
day did you did you
see the US government just released
apparently by accident the project Aqua
stuff did you see this no what's
that this is crazy yeah I guess we're
rolling are we rolling yeah I can wait
till we no no no you can this is just
someone just sent me this this is
Project Aqua yeah hold on I'll
um they just released I think by
accident how's that happened it's kona
blue you familiar with this no Kona BL
is a um it was a program they yeah dude
they I'm going to send this to Homeland
Security just released this send it to
me I'll send it to Jamie and uh you can
air drop it no I got it right right here
I'll just I don't do email or what I
don't know how to airdrop anything you
don't do email
no I haven't done email in many years
really yeah how do you exist I do text
wow just text yeah I don't do email I
don't go on the [__] internet I don't
on the TV I'm not into of that but
anyway um no that stuff is bad you know
yeah I guess that's my isolation tank I
just stay away from that [__] but anyway
that's smart did you text it to me yeah
I did I think I did it didn't get to me
yeah it just s it'll it's a big thing
um okay
so this is so amazing so this is in
there they're talking about this and
this was just released talking about
setting up this program kona blue I
didn't get it uh this is like a UAP
program of some the medical division
will have a small team of medical
analysts under the direction of the
chief physician and Deputy Administrator
they will organized data into a threat
analysis based on medical findings
including but not limited to a deaths
and injuries as a result of interaction
with Advanced Aerospace Vehicles here it
is B Medical injuries as a result of
other anomalies C collateral injuries
psychological effects to family members
so they're admitting that people are
dying
this just like a tweet from yes is this
it a day or
twoo what does that mean other
information do you ever wonder if stuff
like this is just
disinformation yeah
maybe I mean I I wonder if I wonder a
lot of things I'm sure you do but um I
would always always assume that a lot of
this stuff is
nonsense yeah here's what we know
is
that US servicemen have died as a result
of contact with or being in the
proximity of these vehicles and we know
that because there are a lot of Suits
working their way through the VA system
yeah where families you know can't get
compensated for the deaths or injuries
to loved ones because it's all under
wraps top secret well that's just that's
just a fact okay that that is happening
so if there's I guess you know when
there are measurable physical effects of
a phenomenon we can say conclusively the
phenomenon is real right and
um so yeah I mean it is real I mean I
guess we're sort of past the point of
like is it real yeah it's real it's it's
real in that there's these things that
are moving in very bizarre ways and they
have these propulsion systems that
violate what we know about propulsion
systems
retrieving data across dimensional
SpaceTime develop remote viewing coms
and count countermeasures determined
Baseline for physical transport across
dimensional space-time barrier rapid
response Medical Teams for UFO
interaction events so how do they do
this accidentally study conscious
interactions with and control of
technology so I got this from someone in
the US government who's who's who's well
well
look let me let me just start by saying
I you know I don't know anything um
but he sent me this the above is 100%
legit I was read into this program but
told never to tell anyone it's now been
released as you can see um it began as a
result of my old program a
AIP um I signed a document saying I
would never talk about Kona and similar
efforts I can't believe that a would
have released it
look I I you know yeah I mean here's
what we do know is that there's enough
going on in the skies but not just the
skies underwater that U the US military
has been forced to respond to it so like
move aircraft from one place to another
because there are too many of these
objects in the sky that's actually
happened Chris melon just wrote a long
piece about it um so it's real the
government is not controlling it in fact
it's forcing the government DOD to
respond um and we know that there is a a
real effort and has been underway for a
long time to to keep the public from
knowing about it but that's all known
that's established I don't think any
rational person would deny that the
question is like what is it actually I
mean now is sort of the point you have
to ask like what is
this and
um you know so that's how much of it do
you think is out
ours well none of it's ours none of it
well I don't know I mean clearly you
know the US government is huge it's the
largest human organization there are I
think then I think there are 2 million
federal employees and another 10 million
Federal contractors so who are
effectively government employees but
don't have Civil Service protection for
example um so that's 12 million people
in a country of 340 million working for
the federal government so it's kind of
hard to overstate how big the federal
government is and how well-funded and so
to say the government this the
government that no of course it's people
within the government um but yeah
they're working on all kinds of things
obviously uh that are
classified but in general no they they
can't control these objects uh so no
it's not American Technology well or
Russian or Chinese it
predates you know all of that well some
of it does right like for sure the
Kenneth Arnold sightings that was really
early on that was like the 19 early
1950s he was seeing these flying saucers
these discs that were moving over
mountains well right I mean the prophet
Ezekiel writes about it in the first
chapter wheels in the sky yeah that's a
crazy one boy when you read that well it
is crazy if you if you read it it's like
oh wow you know
Andel not just you know the Hebrew
scriptures like it's all over every mhm
the viic textas of course so these These
Are Spiritual phenomenon there's no
evidence they're from another planet I
mean I think that's the op that's the
lie that they're from Mars look space
the atmosphere is really well monitored
right both for military for defense
reasons but also because like it' be
nice to know when asteroids are coming
and there's no evidence has never been
any evidence that there are lots of
these objects these vehicles coming into
our atmosphere from somewhere else some
other planet there's no evidence of that
at all H so they're from here and
they've been here for thousands of years
whatever they are and um it's pretty
clear to me that they're spiritual
entities whatever that means are
Supernatural and which is to say
Supernaturals means above the natural
above the
observable uh nature and um they don't
behave according to the laws of science
as as measured by people you know and um
and they've been here for a long time
and there's a ton of evidence that are
under the ocean and under the ground so
like with that fact set what do you
conclude when did you start having this
opinion that they they were spiritual
and that they've always been here like
when when did this well I didn't know
anything about the topic until
2017 and like was that after the New
York Times piece no it was before it was
before and the things that I saw I mean
like I was and am still a very
conventional person I mean I'm 54 I grew
up in this country in California which
was like
like every assumption about America I
bought completely just completely and I
thought that everyone who questioned
those assumptions was bad I just bought
into the system completely without even
thinking about it and I imagined that I
was like some kind of freeth thinker and
you know I'm going against the grain but
like the my core assumptions were the
you know the assumptions fed to me by
the culture and the government and I
didn't even realize it but anyway I'd
never really thought about UFOs at all
and I've been in journalism since I was
a kid of course I'd run into a lot of
people who had crazy views on a lot of
different topics UFOs 911 circumcision
you know like every whack job in the
world you run into when you're covering
stuff fluoride fluoride right I just
brushed with non fluoride toothpaste
this morning me too um
exactly exactly but probably unlike you
I didn't have any opinions like that I
was like fluide come on you know 911
shut up
UFOs you're [__] crazy you know what
I mean I just like I had this reflex I'm
ashamed of it I'm not bragging about it
but um but it was it was 2017 and really
it was the Trump campaign it wasn't that
I was like so in love with Trump though
I've always liked Trump because you know
he's like hilarious and charming and all
that but I wasn't like a Trumper or
anything um but it was watching that
campaign and particularly his claim that
they were spying on him and I was like
really there not the Intel service and
federal law enforcement FBI do not spy
on presidential campaigns like that's so
out of the realm that's so crazy like
that could never happen because of
course there's no democracy in a system
like that and fundamentally we democracy
an imperfect one it kind of Lumbers
along you know but like it's not
fake and and then that turned out to be
true and I and I knew it was true and
that just blew my mind so I began a
process still ongoing of reassessing a
lot of other things like okay well if
that was not true what else is not true
and what else that they told me was a
conspiracy theory might actually have
some basis in fact and um and then
someone from you know a DOD employee
reached out to me and said actually
there's a ton of evidence that this UFO
thing is
real and really and so I started doing
segments on it um when I worked at at
the TV channel and uh and there was like
a lot of mockery but I was like I don't
care I'm just going to do this and then
of course the second you start you know
better than anybody you start talking
about something then people reach out to
you and some of them are deranged but
some of them aren't at all so I just
started getting a lot of information
from people and meeting with people
mostly in private you know come to my
house let's talk
and and I decided on the basis of what
they told me and then I talked to a lot
of people about it um that actually this
is really a very heavy duty question
actually it's not just it's not the
little green men question it's like a
much bigger question
and it's really bad it's really dark and
and then I stopped then I was like I
don't want to know anymore because it's
not helping me um at all as a person and
I what information did you get that made
you feel like it's
dark it's so dark well first of all the
deception is always bad like lying is
bad in it and it's bad not just in a
legal sense in that it can be illegal to
lie but it's bad it's like bad for you
like it rots you like being a liar makes
you a bad person when you lie you are
serving evil there's a moral quality to
it that's
inescapable and very obvious and only
like advanced advanced civilizations
ignore that lying is bad and so if you
have lying at scale which we have on
this topic it's inherently bad okay so
that's the first level the deeper level
is what are okay so if they're Spiritual
Beings which I believe they
are like it's a binary they're either
you know you're on team good or team bad
you can assign any name to it you want
but like what are these things are they
good or bad and um and I think some of
them are bad and if the US government
knows that or part elements the people
within the US government know that then
you know then they're serving a bad
force and well when you say spiritual
like what what makes you draw that
conclusion that they're spiritual what's
the OB I mean spiritual maybe the wrong
word Supernatural you know they're
beyond nature as we understand it I mean
obviously they are I mean just chart
their physical Behavior it doesn't you
know it goes outside of what we
understand about
physics no visible means of propulsion
you know coming at Indescribable speed
hitting the ocean continuing at speeds
that are impossible under sea I mean in
other words if I if I take a you know 9
mimet r or 762 x 39 and shoot you at 50
yards underwater and a swimming pool and
it's even more intense in salt water
because it's denser you could catch the
bullet if it even makes it to you right
so if you have a craft any object
underwater that's traveling at 500 knots
as measured by sonar right there you're
challenging our understanding physics
like what is that how can that be so
they've they've tracked that they've
tracked things going 500 knots Under the
Sea yeah really yeah much much faster
than any object could can actually go
under under SE yo for
sure oh yeah there's a lot of stuff
going on
underwater and um
a lot and there's video of these things
coming out of the sky into the water and
also emerging from the water right yeah
so it's all so blurry though I don't
think it's trans medium
video yeah I don't think some of it's
that blurry I think some of it's Crystal
Clear um we just don't have access to it
is that what you mean just we haven't
seen itre so they have some stuff for
sure so but there's just a lot going on
under water and it's it's measured and
so whatever I mean these are all again
this is like the most obvious observable
level of it but then you just ask
yourself like what is this
actually and you know if there's been
extensive knowledge of this for decades
like maybe 80 years at least if not
going back to the 30s 90 years um you
know to what to what end so there are
two possible explanations obvious
explanations the first is the one you
often hear which is this is so
heavy that if the public were to know
about it it would be just disruptive it'
be too scary like you don't want to
scare people for no good reason there's
nothing we can do about it and you also
don't want to suggest that you know the
US military isn't capable of protecting
the country the
Homeland um and it does suggest that if
you can't control these objects in your
airspace and that's known they can't
that's known okay then that's just a
limit to the power of the US Military
and you don't want to tell people that
because then they like won't believe
that they're safe I get it
but then there's a deeper level which is
like okay what's your relationship with
these
things what is the US government's
relationship with these things and
there's evidence that there is a
relationship and that it's a
longstanding and that raises like a lot
of questions about intent and um and so
like what is that and I just personally
decided um you know and and people have
been hurt by these things you know
that's a fact that's a fact it's a no
fact it's a provable fact and killed and
I'm not saying millions of people have
been killed by whatever these things are
but people have been killed and it's
known because it's working its way
through the courts out of the VA so um I
don't know an object that is by
definition Supernatural it's above the
laws of nature as we understand them and
that has resulted in the deaths of
people we don't spend enough time
thinking about like what that adds up to
like not good actually not good how many
people do you think have died from these
things I don't know but I mean I and is
it radiation sickness is it like what
what is what's the so the person that I
talked to I interviewed someone who was
a Stanford Medical School Professor
who's who's out there and worth talking
to by the way and a um talkinging about
Gary Nolan that's exactly who I'm
talking about who's effectively an
expert witness in these cases so he's an
expert in brain injury do you know him
yeah yeah entirely credible person um
checks all the boxes that I care about
he's he's got patents so he's like a lot
of Stanford University professors he's
like independently Rich he flew to I
live in a remote place and he flew to my
place at his own expense because he
wanted to tell the story so he he's got
no profit motive here he's the most
highly credentialed person at the
University practically Stanford Medical
School we consider that a big deal uh
and he's worked on this for you know
over 10 years um assess ing the injuries
to US
servicemen from being in close proximity
to these objects or having contact with
these objects and his conclusion as you
know because you've talked to him is
that there's some kind of energy coming
off here that scrambles people's brains
or kills them and it's not exactly
radiation um at least in his telling to
me so anyway but the point is people
have
died yeah
and so you know it it does raise a lot
of a lot of questions about like what
the hell right what the hell American
citizens have died and you're hiding it
why are you hiding that why would you
hide
that perhaps because they don't have any
explanations because they they're it's
so beyond our comprehension that they're
still trying to piece it together like I
would wonder how much interaction they
really do have with these things like if
I was from another planet or if I was
some interdimensional being I don't know
how much I'd give a [__] about the
president I don't know how much I'd give
a [__] about the government I would
probably look at this infantile race
this species this
bizarre territorial Apes with
thermonuclear weapons this very weird
species I I'd probably look at them as
very chaotic and uh I wouldn't really
have much concern for who's running
it especially if they have the ability
to travel at insane speeds and go
undetected
and well it depends like that okay so
the template that you're using to
understand this is like science fiction
right these are an advanced race of
beings from somewhere else but the
template that every other Society before
us has used is a spiritual one there is
a whole world that we can't see that
acts on people a supernal world it's
acting on us all the time for good and
bad every society has thought this
before ours in fact every society in all
recorded history has thought that until
I'll be specific August 1945 When we
dropped the atom bombs on hoshima
Nagasaki and all of a sudden the West is
just officially secular we're God there
is no God but us and that's the world
that we have grown up in but that's an
anomally like no one else has ever
thought that there's never been a
society that thought that every other
Society has assumed and they've had all
kinds of different explanations and the
details differ but the core idea does
not differ and never has differed from
caves until now that we're being acted
on by spiritual forces at all times and
so to someone born before or living
before 1945 I think it would have been
much more
obvious that this is the thing that
every society has written about and in
fact that battle that unseen battle
around us that spiritual battle has like
been the basis of every society of every
Rel every religion not just Christianity
so like it just once you discard your
very very recent assumptions relatively
speaking about how the world Works
you're like well that kind of seems like
the obvious explanation right H it's not
that obvious to
me so what's what's more obvious do you
think well I I I don't think there's an
obvious explanation I think if I had to
guess some of this stuff is ours and
some of these things are propulsion
systems that they theorized way back in
the 1950s anti-gravity propulsion
systems things that can operate without
igniting Fuel and pushing something out
that they operate in some completely
different way that utilizes gravity and
almost can instantaneously transport to
new places essentially fold space
time um I don't
know so there there's there's things
that the government does
where they have these
programs and the people that are sworn
into these programs whether they the
physicists or you know the metallurgists
or whoever these people are that are
working on these programs they don't
tell anybody all their phones are
monitored everything's monitored there's
a so there's a culture of secre ism
that's pretty intense and it's not
inconceivable that over the course of
the last 70 plus years of them
theorizing
and then eventually implementing some of
these things that they've developed
drones that could move in ways that this
the conventional the people that
understand conventional propulsion
systems could not imagine and that they
figured out a way to do this and to keep
it secret and we're probably not the
only ones work on these
things but where did they get that
information and you know have you you
know Diana Pula you know her work like
they they describe these crafts these
crash crafts as donations which is
fascinating like that they're left there
the crashed retrieval program the
crashed UAP retrieval program is
essentially they're going like figure
this out we're going to crash this thing
here you figure this out and the
question is if that's true okay where
are these things coming from are they if
if there's something that is so Advanced
that it's decided to leave us a little
Trinket for us to back engineer is that
from another dimension is that from here
is that from some realm that we just
don't have access to is it from another
planet are we we have drones that are on
other planets right now we have a drone
on Mars we have you know the lunar
Rovers we have satellites that we send
to observe and photograph other planets
we just got really high detailed
photographs of Jupiter they're pretty
amazing but if something was like us on
another planet and but lived
uninterrupted with technology advancing
for a thousand years 10,000 years a
million years more than us what would
that be like and how much would we be
able to understand of what we're seeing
what would be what would be we be able
to see and this idea that we monitor our
skies sure but if something just appears
and disappears essentially
instantaneously if something literally
can fold time can fold space and just
tra Traverse between immense distances
almost
instantaneously what are we going to see
what are we going to see and also like
what kind of detection systems do we
have we have radar we have visual we
have uh a bunch of different
military-based detection systems to look
out for enemy crafts and airships and
all that stuff but if you're dealing
with something that's a million years
more advanced than us how much would we
we be able to detect well so I I think
we're pointing to the same question I
mean I have no doubt that the US
government has technology that we don't
know the details of that makes sense
sure but like where did it come from
right um I'm not even sure this is a
separate question but related not sure
we really know where nuclear technology
came from um actually when you really
yes like the Manhattan Project yeah like
we know the Manhattan know something
about the Manhattan Project but like
where exactly did that you know came
from Germany German scientists were
working on
okay um the one p a separate
conversation but the one person I know
who's really pushed that I was writing a
book on it um who's a trustworthy person
and a friend of mine I know you know him
um said to me actually I spent a year
working on this and I One the closer I
got to like okay but what's the Genesis
like where the where did this what was
the mo what was the Isaac Newton Apple
on the head o gravity's real moment for
fision
not clear weird I don't know the answer
but but here's the point clearly
government has technology that we don't
we're not read in on right of course
but so that doesn't answer the question
why have people seen these objects in
the skies for thousands of years
confirmed and what are they and maybe
they're from another planet and my only
point is there's no evidence of that
there's a huge amount a massive Corpus
of evidence that they're seen by people
in our atmosphere you know on Earth
looking up or in a submarine looking out
and what is that and by the way to your
point like we can't see them coming into
our atmosphere because they don't want
to be seen well then why do they want to
be seen by people on earth like if they
if the technolog is that advanced and
clearly it is why do they make
themselves visible in the first place
well you know when we study primates uh
one of the things that we do if do you
ever watch chimp Nation on NX have a TV
but the sound of it uh it's an amazing
documentary on Netflix that details
these embedded scientists uh in the
Congo and what's really fascinating
about it is that this group of
scientists or you know related
scientists have been there for 20 plus
years so these chimps have become
entirely accustomed to having human
beings near them so this very specific
rules you stay within 20 yards of them
you if they come closer you back up you
never have food ever you can't bring any
food there cuz they'll they'll [__] you
up and just steal your food if they find
out you have food you're in real trouble
oh yeah they tear you apart and they
kill each other so they they'll
definitely kill you and so when they
have done this the chimps have become
accustomed to them being there and The
Chimps behave completely normally The
Chimps see them as just an innocuous
part part of their environment they're
not food and they're not enemy they
don't ever intrude they don't try to
challenge them they don't make eye
contact so they don't worry about the
people at all so they behave completely
like
chimps and if I was an advanced species
and I was studying people and I wanted
the human beings to eventually kind of
catch up right like you're introducing
technology that they call donations
crash Vehicles figure figure out what
fiber optics are here you go check this
out figure this out try to figure that
out maybe it'll take you decades maybe
it'll take you more but you are
accelerating the technological evolution
of this Advanced species on this planet
and one way to do that would be for what
purpose I wonder well that's a very good
question my my belief is
that biological intelligent life is a
essentially a caterpillar and it's a
caterpillar that's making a cocoon and
it doesn't even know why it's doing it
it's just doing it and that cocoon is
going to give birth to artificial life
Digital Life it's going to give birth to
a new life form and I think we're real
close to that I think we're way closer
than that to that than most people would
ever want to Adit agree I agree and I
think but can we assign a like a value
to that is that good or
bad that's a good question it depends
universally I think it's the path I
think it's what happens I
think what this thing is if if you
extrapolate if you take the concept of a
a sentient artificial intelligence that
has the ability to utilize all the
information that every human being has
on Earth at a level of computing that's
far beyond the capabilities of the human
mind and all of our supercomputers that
currently exist because it'll design
much better computers it'll use quantum
computers it'll have the ability to
recode things and change things it'll
make better versions of itself so
instead of biological evolution which is
very slow it takes a long time
relatively it takes it's pretty quick
really when you think about it like how
long it's not that long to go from being
a single cell organism to being a human
being flying a plane really atively over
the course of a billion years if you
think about how long the universe has
been around but it's slow compared to
technological Evolution I mean a hundred
years ago we didn't have [__] and now we
have we could send videos from your
phone and it'll hit New Zealand in a
second it's crazy the stuff that we have
now is beyond imagination it's
essentially magic for people a 100 years
ago if that keeps going
it's ultimately going to leave to a life
form and if that life form has now
untethered it has doesn't have any
problems with biological evolution now
it's just about information and
implementing the technology that's
available and then increasing that
technology and making it better and
better it essentially becomes a
God because if if you give it enough
time it it it doesn't it has the ability
to make better versions of itself which
will in turn make better versions of
itself self it has the ability to
utilize everything it has the the
understanding of everything that exists
in the universe ex black holes Dark
Matter everything and it probably has
the ability to harness that or even
reproduce
that so if you take artificial sentient
in intelligence and it has this super
accelerated path of technological
Evolution and you give Art
general intelligence sensient artificial
intelligence far beyond human beings you
give it a thousand years alone to to
make better and better versions of
itself where does that go that goes to a
god it it literally create un kind of
God so like I I think of it this way so
the first stage of the Industrial
Revolution consisted of people building
machines that were stronger than the
human body right right so the steam
powered Loom sure the back hoo com
combustion engine they replace they
replace muscles right right so that's
what the machine does it it becomes
stronger than the human body the second
stage which we're in the middle of
consists of creating machines that are
more powerful than the human
mind that's what Computing is and I
would say AI or super competing it's
just
that exponentially
uh but that doesn't make it a God in the
sense that the machine however powerful
it is any more than a backhoe is a God
because it can dig a trench faster than
100 men it it's still something that
people created so the story hasn't
really changed at the center of the
story are
people and their creative power may lead
to unintended consequences but the
machines that they build did not make
the universe and did not make people
people made the machines right so if and
I but I would say the part I agree with
is there's a spiritual component here
for
sure people will worship AI as a god AI
Ted kazinski was likely right will get
away from us we will be controlled by
the thing that we made all those are bad
like that's just bad and we need to say
unequivocally it's bad it's bad to be
controlled by machines right machines
are helpmates like they we created them
to help us to make our lives better not
to take orders from them um so I I don't
know why we're not having any of these
conversations right now we're just
acting as if this is like some kind of
virus like Co that spreads across the
world inexorably there's nothing we can
do about it just wait to get it it's
like no if we agree that the outcome is
bad which and specifically it's bad for
people we should care what's good for
people that's all we should care about
is it good for people or not if it's bad
for people then we should strangle it in
its crib right now right and why to blow
up the data centers like I don't why is
that hard if it's actually going to
become what you just
described which which is a threat to
people
Humanity life then we have a a moral
obligation to murder it immediately and
since it's not alive we don't need to
feel bad about that well you could say
the same about the atomic bomb right yes
you could and you could say that we have
to develop it like Oppenheimer felt
before the Nazis did I love that how'd
that
work how'd that work well I love by the
way that people on my side I'll just say
I'll just admit it on the right you know
have spent the last 80 years defending
dropping nuclear weapons on civilians
like are you joking right that's just
like Prima fascia evil if you can't well
if we hadn't done that then this that
the other thing that was actually a
great Savings of life no it's wrong to
drop nuclear weapons on people and if
you find yourself arguing that it's a
good thing to drop nuclear weapons on
people then you are evil like it's it's
not a it's not a tough one right it's
not a hard call for it's not a hard call
for me so with that in mind like why
would you want nuclear weapons it's like
just a Mindless childish sort of
intellectual exercise to justify like oh
no it's really good because someone else
get how about no how about like spending
all of your effort to prevent this from
happening would you kill Baby Hitler you
know famously
right um so I don't know why we're
sitting back and allowing this to happen
if we really believe it will extinguish
the human race or enslave the human race
like how can that be good well if God
creates everything if God created the
universe and God creates people God
probably creates a process and we think
that we are very important because we
are very important to us but are are we
very important in a universal sense not
really like if the Earth just imploded
and disappeared if the sun went
supernova and our whole solar system was
blown to bits the universe is still
exists it depends how wi for sure in in
our the end as Conan O'Brien the famous
philosopher once said every grave goes
unvisited which is true and that's an
important perspective pull out the lens
a little bit does it really matter no it
doesn't but it does matter do your kids
how about this do your children matter
yes sure do their lives matter would you
die for them yes of course everything
matters if you're not comfortable it
matters if you're sitting here like you
don't want to wear headphones like let's
not wear headphones that matters
everything matters the the I mean at
scale what matters most like right is it
that is the evil right the evil is the
it's the same thing is saying the
necessary evil of dropping nuclear bombs
on civilians is if you don't do that
then there will be more evil then more
things will happen it's kind of the same
thing like it doesn't it well it comes
from the same place which is hubris like
imagining you're God you have unlimited
power and you have omniscience you can
imagine what the future's going to be
you can't you're [__] idiot you're a
person like you can't even make your
wife happy like the limits of your power
are really obvious the limits of your
wisdom same so like don't jump into [__]
big things whose outcomes you can't
predict with certainty like you can't
know go in with humility I guess that's
what I'm saying right so yeah um and do
what you can knowing that you're
probably going to screw it up and you
probably won't achieve your goal but
like you should try and on the AI
question everyone I've ever talked to
but I'm hardly an expert I don't own a
computer okay but um Everybody I've ever
talked to and there's many people like
yeah it's you know could get away from
us and enslave us well let's say no to
slavery how's that is that a tough one
not for me yeah I mean and maybe a good
use of nuclear weapons would be to hit
the data
centers no I'm I'm Ser like why is that
crazy it's not it's not if you think
that human beings are the end of this
evolutionary CH well what else is some
supercomputer in a data center outside
Dallas airport no I mean you know what I
mean like I don't actually think that
individuals I don't think I'm that
important my life is that important I
don't I will die I know that and I try
to keep that in mind every day but
you're important to everybody that you
that cares about you you're important to
the people around if we don't think if
we don't think people are important then
what do we think is important I guess
that's what I'm saying it's not
necessarily that we don't think people
are important but if if if evolution is
real and if there is this constant I
don't know but it's it's it's visible
like you can measure it in certain
animals
you can measure adaptation yeah but
there's no evidence that EV in fact I
think we've kind of given up on the idea
Evolution the theory of evolution is
articulated by Darwin is like kind of
not true in what in what
sense well in the most basic sense the
idea that you know all life emerge from
a single cell organism and over time and
there would be a fossil record of that
and there's not and there's not a fossil
record of uh transitionary species like
species that are adapting to its
environment of record of and you see it
in your own life I mean I have a lot of
dogs I I see adaptation in dogs you know
through the sure um litter to litter but
no there's no evidence at all that none
zero that you know people you know
evolve seamlessly from a single cell
amoeba no there's not there's not
there's no chain in the fossil record of
that at all and that's why you don't
actually hear people you hear them make
reference to Evolution because the
theory of adaptation is clearly
obviously
true but Darwin's theory is totally un
that's why it's still a theory almost
200 years later you know um no we have
not found that at all and I can't even
guess I mean I have my own theories on
it but they're not proven what are your
theories God created people you know
distinctly and animals I mean I think
that's like I think what every person on
Earth thought until the mid 19th century
actually right but it's not a new idea
they they didn't have computer they
didn't have a a general understanding
that we have today of the process do you
think we understand more now yes really
you don't think that we understand more
today we understand way less we
understand so little that we're actually
sitting here allowing like a bunch of
greedy stupid childless childless
software engineers in Northern
California to like flirt with the
extinction of mankind so no pre previous
generations would be like what no stop
and um we're not doing that because but
they wouldn't have done that even with
the nuclear bomb I mean obviously the
Manhattan Project was done in secrecy
but they wouldn't have stopped it
because the imperative of getting this
weapon before Hitler got the weapon was
what well Hitler was kind of done by
then um the Russians had pretty much
extinguished any hope that that would
continue but but not the you know we
were in the middle of the logic of war
the commencement of the Manhattan
Project for sure and but the logic was
the same it was you know four years of
got to beat the other guy got it and I
don't I don't mean to sound too
judgmental about the bomb I know why
they built it okay but you just wonder
why nobody in the middle of that thought
is this really a and some of them did
think it I'm sure they did I mean
Oppenheimer himself of course large
organizations don't respond to the moral
qualms of individuals very well uh so
that was whatever it's it's well known
what happened but no we should pause and
ask is the machine we're building worth
having and nobody seems to do that and
there are all kinds of economic forces
which nobody ever mentions that drive
that heedlessness that stupidity like
California for example um is completely
the state both of us have lived in is
like like collapsing and they're betting
everything on AI for the the tax base is
going to be dependent on this technology
working and is what they're betting on
of course that AI is did you see the the
most recent thing about the amount of
billions of dollars they spent on the
homeless problem with no trackable
results well they've had massive results
they've increased the homeless
population dramatically if you pay for
something you get more of it and that
would include fentanyl addicts oh
absolutely it's been a wild success I
actually talked to Kevin Newsome the
other day did you really yeah and um
what's that like does he smell like
sulfur it was by phone I was talking him
on the phone such a weird um he smell
like that was too fast for me sulfur and
hair grease
yeah no but I was making I was making
fun of I shouldn't even make fun of it
cuz it's so tragic but what's happened
to the state and people living on the
street and what is his non- gasy
perspective he's said go back to Russia
you like Russia so much I was like you
know actually I'm originally from San
Francisco but um I can't live there
because he really told you to go back to
Russ of course I mean he was laughing
whatever um he's a perfectly Charming
guy they all are in person of course
anyway my I'm so far a field but my
point is AI is being driven by the greed
of politicians to some extent um and
you'll notice that AI by the way as a
fact those data centers that drive our
Digital Life which is not life it's
actually death mostly but um I mean
they're the biggest power draw I mean
what will how much electricity does AI
require like more than countries our
grid can't handle AI just as a practical
matter well our grid can't handle
electric cars Well it can't handle air
conditioning in the state of California
where I'm from so right if you live east
of I5 where it's really hot and you're
not getting those ocean breezes like
your they have brown outs like in South
Africa it's Johannesburg now so but
here's what's interesting is that none
of the global warming cultists seem to
have any concerns at all about AI why is
that just like they don't have concerns
about John K's G4 like somehow that's
exempt really AI is going to draw more
electricity than anything else in the
United States more than steel production
okay used to and you don't have a
problem with that but you're totally
against energy because it's destroying
the planet but AI gets a carve out even
though it's going to be the number one
energy draw in the United States let's
go through your reasoning on that
they're probably not aware well they're
tot they're not aware they're mad about
my wood stove I heat with wood they're
mad about my wood stove they don't want
an outdoor barbecue they don't like a
gas stove no they're way into the
details on this stuff except somehow AI
isn't a problem but do you think that
they're informed because this is not a
narrative that you ever hear you never
hear uh on the news I grew up in a world
where a wood stove was considered
holesome and natural and now it's
considered oh it's the best and the heat
is the I I have a Woodfired sauna which
I use every day and it's the great you
know it's one how do you make sure it's
the right temperature is it like U like
an Offset Smoker like you have to kind
of fiddle with it amazing to get the
right it's time consuming now I have a
finish um the fins are geniuses but I
have a Finnish uh stove in it and it's
incredibly prec I don't know if you ever
use a wood stove but there's a
carburetor on it basically that lets in
air like a like an Offset Smoker yeah
exactly and it's so precise I mean it's
it's absolutely crazy I mean you move it
you know a third of an inch and it just
like the flame changes so I use Birch
which I love and um the whole process
takes a while get it to 200 which
probably takes an hour and 20 I mean
it's it's a Thing You Like It Hot Like
It Hot yeah yeah 200 yeah I do it every
I wear a sauna hat so oh okay does that
help which is embarrassing the wool hat
yeah well it's it's felt yeah I bought
one of those I never wore it it's
incredible yeah what's the difference
I'll tell you you're cuz you're duny I'm
so boring on this subject going at this
like my wife and kids are like you see I
have one you know we're you're speaking
to the car the best
go Scandinavia um it's like the one
thing if your name is Carlson uh it's
the one thing to be proud of and your
people like they're so sad and defeated
and pathetic but um saunas are still
great but anyway uh the sauna hat so
your head heats up much faster because
it's higher but also because it's got
all the capillaries in your head all
blood vessels in your head so the point
of a of a sauna is to bake right so you
want to stay hot as long as you can then
you reap the benefits and you also get
the Solitude and the prayer time or the
meditation or whatever in your Cedar
church and but you can't stay in a sauna
that's really hot very long because your
head heats up right so the Sonic hat the
felt hat the B hat as they call it
insulates your head so you can you can
really stay hot a long long
time um it makes a you really should do
it so is it just because it makes it
more comfortable is that the idea if
your head overheats you know it just
overheats and you want is you want to
cook evenly just like on a barbecue you
know you really do and so you know you
sit on the bench with your feet up you
want to be as flat as you possibly can
to cook evenly and to stay that way so I
do I try to do 20 minutes I have my you
know my timer U my egg timer with the
sand going through The Hourglass and I
which goes to 15 minutes but I try to
stay an extra five if I can and um and I
couldn't without the B hat interesting
it's like eight bucks on Amazon
well worth it yeah I I have one like I
said I just don't use it but I I do
they're embarrassing and you look like a
tool wearing it yeah but you shouldn't
have but no one's looking in there
anyway well that's right you don't s
with other people right well I do
sometimes yeah Comics we get in here
yeah yeah yeah when we uh train together
we all get in the saong together
afterwards it's fun The Rock was in
there with us no way yeah the rock
worked out with us then sat in the sauna
with us it was fun got in the Cal plunge
with us oh that's pretty great it was
fun is he a good dude he's a great guy
really nice guy like really I've heard
that I don't know him but I've heard
that he's a good you know some people
fake humble they fake it to look cool
it's pretty obvious yeah he's not doing
that he's he's a real guy like the
measure of humility is really really
simple can you tell the truth about
yourself yeah you know yeah well you
know are you just are you cool to be
around like he he gives real hugs you
know he's a real guy I love he's real
he's a real guy and we when we hung out
with him we were I hung out with them
for hours we worked out for like 2 hours
and then we got in the sauner together
we all hung out then we did a podcast
together he's a genuinely nice guy like
You' you'd be able to sniff something
out you can tell like something you tell
something you know people are hiding
stuff yeah but um so yeah I do I've done
the SAA with other people I do it by
myself so no one sees my SAA I do it at
196 degrees I do it for 25 minutes and
uh us I don't that's intense 196 for 25
minutes is a lot yeah the last five
minutes are rough and I used to only do
20 but lately I've been doing 25 really
yeah just because it's more
uncomfortable the whole idea is just to
to make it more uncomfortable I want it
to be very hard to do so that the rest
of my day is pretty easy so really hard
workout cold plunge starts the day
that's the the the first thing I do is
hard it's 3 minutes at 33 degrees it
sucks and then I get out of there and
then I work out so um it's really
impressive I me night
I had the opposite training as a young
man which was the goal was like french
toast you know what I mean French toast
grind out the cigarettes in the syrup
when you're done yeah well I I started
doing martial arts when I was a young
man and when I got into it it was the
first thing that I had ever did that
first of all gave me a real
understanding of the value of discipline
and hard work yeah because uh you can
get as good as the amount of effort that
you put forth and if you put more effort
and you're more tense and you're more
driven than other people you beat them
and you start beating everyone and you
start you start becoming this thing that
you never thought you could be which is
someone who's extraordinary at something
that's very dangerous and so that was my
formulation as a man like that that
helped me go from being this like
confused kid to being someone who
understands like oh there's a path and
most people don't want to do it but if
you could do it if you can do this
dangerous thing that people are
terrified of and just do it ruthlessly
all day long like live it I lived at the
gym I mean I taught all day long I I
trained all day long my my whole life
was dedicated to martial arts so I got
really good really quick and it it
changed the whole trajectory of my life
and it instilled in me this
understanding of the value of dedication
and of a singular commitment to
something to really being while you're
doing you're not distracted you're fully
focused on
improving and through that you could
apply that to all aspects of your life
but we all encounter difficult things in
life and there's this saying that I love
it's a really great saying that the the
hardest thing that's ever happened to
you is the hardest thing that's ever
happened to you if it's a parking ticket
or if it's your parents being blown up
by a drone it's still the hardest thing
that's ever happened to you if you've
had an incredibly easy life like most
people today yeah they complain about
the dumbest [__] [__] because to them
that is their primary focus they don't
have a real existential threat you
remember how nice everybody was after
911 very it was crazy California was
patriotic there's [__] flags on
everybody's car everybody was friendly I
went to New York City it was like a
totally different place everybody was so
friendly applauding when firemen walked
in they were Heroes everybody was a hero
and that's because they had encountered
something that was way harder than they
were were accustomed to and it just put
things into perspective so for me
training and really hard workouts and
doing difficult things like the sauna
there's a lot of health benefits to it
too but the mental benefits to it are
really primary for me because it makes
it's impressive I didn't have a
childhood like that at all and we were
decadent
unfortunately and uh so those are
lessons that I learned much much later
but yeah it's that's a that's a good I
think it's a if it doesn't destroy you I
think it's a great way to you don't have
to do it the way I do it you could do
other stuff you could do yoga you could
do hikes you could do doing things for
the sake of the difficulty in doing them
yes I I love that again that was not not
not my training at all yeah um I was
very lucky that it was mine but more
importantly it gave me a tool to
mitigate the stress of regular life and
the especially the stress of this kind
of life that I live you you need
something to mitigate that you agree
with that completely you'll go crazy
yeah you know removing yourself from it
a little bit has always worked for me
you know nature Works a very very well
yeah animals contact with animals people
you love sure less digital experiences
fewer digital experiences for
sure I think that stuff's not good for
you it's just so obviously not good for
you I was having this conversation with
Michelle Dow yesterday she is uh a woman
who survived an apocalyptic cult she was
raised in apocalyptic cult and kicked
out when she was 17 cuz she snuck out to
go see the color purple they weren't
allowed to go see movies she had never
seen a movie until she was 17 she'd
never seen a movie and her first movie
was the color purple and then they
kicked her out they I can kind of see
that I mean what about Raiders of the
Lost Arc or something The Color Purple
was the first movie she'd ever seen I
know but like you see one movie and it's
the color purple a boy invited her to
the movie but could you imagine never
seeing a movie or even a television show
your whole life and then seeing a boy
who wanted to see the color purple like
there's so much going on here Joe well
this boy was a guy who had left the
church and so she was in contact with
him and you know and he was saying hey
there's a whole world out here you want
to go see the movie and she's like okay
let's go yeah I mean obvious look I'm
totally against Colts um obviously on
the other hand you do you got to ask
yourself like I don't know is your
average Amish teenager
happier than your average conventional
American Teenager on Instagram and of
course the answer is oh yeah well they
certainly have less instances of autism
which is really fascinating it's very
very fish have less autism yeah there's
almost none well I'm not surprised it's
extremely rare what do we think that is
I wonder I really did I can think of a
couple yeah that's funny I don't want to
go Bobby Kennedy that's the problem if
you go Bobby Kennedy they'll come for
you the question is why why look and I
don't I don't know the answer but how is
that not in the de debate how is that
not in the conversation well it's not
only not in the conversation you're
punished for adding it to the
conversation and so like we are dancing
around antiva conspiracy theories right
now why why be on the defensive it's
like if you purport to represent science
and you're mad about a question and
you're ignoring data yeah but even with
in the absence of data right science is
the is a process yes it's not a result
it's a way of doing things and at the
core of science is asking questions
including unlikely questions right that
that's what science is right and if you
don't allow that then you know you're
you may be doing something but what
you're not doing is science we we can we
can say that conclusively so for people
to wrap themselves in the mantle of
Science and attack you for asking a
question um you know they're frauds and
I don't know how they have the moral
High Ground in this I don't think they
do but I think it's the same kind of
mindset that allows people to create the
nuclear bomb because you say listen like
like let's we're not even saying that
vaccines cause autism but let's let's
say this if you're looking at all the
data of all the things that cause autism
and you see that the vaccine schedule
ramps up considerably and then you
have autism which seems to at least be
more diagnosed than ever before people
will instantly say we stopped polio we
stopped small poox vaccines have saved
millions of lives and they're probably
right we Dro that bomb to keep Germany
from dropping that bomb we need nuclear
weapons so that other people don't have
nuclear weapons we do a thing that maybe
has some negative effects but is overall
good and I think you can kind of apply
that sort of logic and reason as a human
being to very messy issues I think
people do that way people do that with
abortion right sure they do that with
abortion they a woman has a right to
choose reproductive Freedom they say all
these things and then you say okay what
if the baby is near
term what if it's 6 months old what if
it's s months old and people don't want
to have that conversation a woman has
the right to choose you're a fascist
stay out of women's bod do woman have a
right to kill you if you annoy her or
inconvenience her well it's this is
where gets weird like when is it a life
but it is one of those things that to me
is a human problem whereas humans have
these very
messy interactions with some things that
don't line up with their ideology and
there's an ideology of science worship
there's an ideology of authoritarian
worship the the bodies of science have
bestowed the truth if you ignore it
you're science denier and you know
that's those are political terms or
theological terms um they're not terms
rooted in science and look I we all make
tradeoffs constantly you know what
there's you know everything's bad it's a
[__] Sandwich versus a [__] croissant
I'll take the [__] croissant it's
smaller you know like that's that's a
daily experience for everybody so I get
that and I don't think everything is a
moral absolute either you know we don't
even know um sometimes whether a
decision will result in good or bad so
like it's very complicated I totally
agree with that what I object to is the
absence of reason right like you have to
believe because I think it's true that
if you're
reasonable that you can reach maybe not
the perfect decision but a better
decision and if we don't believe that
then we're just in the land of
Witchcraft and let's just admit it so
the lack of reason is what freaks me out
well it's ideological capture right
because there's certain things that if
you are on the right side of these
subjects the correct side whatever your
your ideology believes you can't you
can't differ from the doctrine there's a
there's a very clear do religion then it
is yeah it is religion so I'm very pro-
religion but you can't have a religion
that's too stupid and destructive if
your religion winds up hurting a lot of
people then I'm against your religion
like that's right yeah I think but even
some really good religions have aspects
of them that you could say were overall
detrimental to the people that were sure
absolutely you could say encountered
with them I think
that that kind of thinking I think cult
thinking whether it's Scientology or
whether it's Christianity or there's
like a type of thinking or it's woke
woke is clearly a cult it's a mind virus
and I think that you call it's it's so
trit to call it that now it's like
whatever this thing is this left ISM
this Marxist sort of ideology that's
waving its flag and and indoctrinating
people in this country it's very similar
to all kinds of religions it's very
similar to
fundamentalist religions that have
always existed in that everybody has to
believe very specific things and you
can't differ you can't differ from the
doctrine and when so here's another way
to think about it that I've been think
I've been meditating on this a lot
it yes religion politics they're all
kind of melding it's hard to know where
one ends and another begins right so
maybe a simpler and more useful way to
think about it is truth or
falsehood lying or
honesty maybe just assess everything
that way is someone lying I don't care
what your justification for it is lying
about vaccines they've lied a lot about
vaccines and they've done it I think in
most cases because they feel like
they're serving some greater good right
well that's the narrative right right we
can't tell people that there are vaccine
injuries because they won't get vaccines
which are good for a big population I
understand the thinking but you how
about this you can't participate in
lying you can't lie you can't lie and
you period though you can't lie about
anything just don't lie about anything
try to tell the truth all the time if
you can't say something that's true just
don't say it right you're not required
to say everything you think obviously
and you shouldn't say everything you
think but you should never lie and if
you just stick with that like you get
pretty quickly back to reason and Order
don't you yeah yeah no you're making
complete sense and I think that um this
is the problem when people have
information and power above other people
well right that's for sure which is the
problem of governments which is also the
problem of cult leaders yeah you know
cult leaders they get completely
infatuated with this idea of being
omnipro and this this power that has
control over giant swats of people and
you get to dictate their behavior and
you get to tell them what to think
that's very intoxicating and it's it's
it's common it's common in that it's
always existed throughout human history
it's a thing that people do when they
get power they abuse the [__] out of it
and if they think that you're too stupid
to know the truth and that they're
better than you because they do think
they're better than you because they're
running things it's a natural
inclination it's a natural thought that
people have if they're the ones if if
you guys are a bunch of dopes that uh
are are just listening to my orders and
I tell you how to live your life and
what to do I'm naturally going to think
I'm better than you well that's I mean
people have live lived under those
systems since there have been systems
but always what makes it particularly
ging and hard to live with is when you
call that system a democracy right
that's too dishonest for me it's I would
much rather live in a monarchy where
everyone thinks the King has been
assigned by God to rule over us and his
whims are law and you know that makes
sense I don't like it but at least it
has internal coherence right when they
stand up and pass a $60 billion funding
bill for Ukraine when 70% of the
population doesn't want it when they're
ignoring the actual problems in our
country like the economy and the border
and they're calling in Congress over the
weekend to pass something that people
don't want while ignoring the things
that people do want and if they do the
same kind of thing again and again for
like 50 years and they call it a
democracy that will drive you insane
yeah because it's just too dishonest why
not just say we don't give a [__] what
you want we are getting something out of
this Ukraine funding whether it's like
the thrill of being Masters of the
Universe or whether it's money from the
defense contractors whatever we're
getting out of it is more important to
us than your opinion this is not
self-government you don't run this
country we do shut up and Obey if they
at least said that you'd be like okay I
get it those are the terms but if I get
another [__] lecture from Joe scarre
about defending democracy when this is
not a democracy it's not even a close
approximation of a democracy then I'm
going to go crazy cuz I just can't deal
with the lying yeah does that make sense
it does make sense what's interesting is
that there are people saying that now
and I think that's a relatively new
thing in terms of mainstream media it's
and I consider what you do on X
mainstream media I mean this is what
we're on right now is essentially
mainstream media it used to be you could
call it there's corporate controlled
media
I agree and and that used to be
mainstream media mainstream media used
to be CNN it's not really anymore
mainstream media is what in terms of the
volume consumed more people are
consuming things on Twitter on X than
there are on anything else they're
they're consuming information through
the internet through YouTube for good or
for bad whether it's correct or
incorrect they're consuming information
in in different forms now than ever
before so more people are saying what
you're saying than have ever said it
before and when when people lie and when
people [__] and Gaslight it's more
offensive now than it's ever been before
because there's so much access to truth
that it's just you could see it now if
you're paying attention if you're not a
boomer who only reads the newspaper you
you pay attention and you see it you go
this is horseshit but it's it's like I
guess what bothers me is that the lies
aren't sophisticated no I mean I look
back over my Now sort of long life and
I'm recognizing all the times that I was
lied to but you know I didn't know I was
being lied to they kind of pulled it off
there's something incredibly insulting
and demeaning to tell me a lie when I
know it's a lie and you know I know it's
a lie we both know it's a lie but you're
demanding that I pretend to believe it
what you're really saying is I have no
respect for you you're like my dog right
you're a
slave like I'm in that you participate
in my lie right the lack of stealth um
really do that I'm not explaining very
well but that that really bothers me a
well there's no real other way to lie
you you like some of these lies like
politicians like did you see that
conversation that AOC had with that man
they brought in for the the Biden case
and they were talking about uh what what
crimes and she was she was like grilling
this guy what crimes did you see Joe B
did he steal anything did he steal bread
like I forgot what she said but and he
was trying to explain what they were
Rico crimes and she was saying Rico is
not a crime it's a category of crime
like okay all right but tell that to the
jevy family not only that it's so dumb
to say that publicly like and say it
with confidence and to tell a person
that's the thing the the marriage of
inaptitude and high self-esteem is it's
really the marker of our time it's like
I have nothing against dumb people at
all my dogs are dumb and I love my dogs
no I'm serious I don't think God cares
about your intelligence right only
people care and so it's not a moral
category and stupidity is not a I mean
someone with Down Syndrome I I really
believe better people than I am you know
more likely to go to heaven so I'm not
attacking her for being dumb but the
idea that a dumb person has no the White
House PR secretaries in the same
category who has no idea she's dumb and
she really thinks like she won prize
like she's the most impressive like I'm
white house prary because I'm the best
talker in
America so it's so crazy and yet the
smartest people I know are very often
like sort of well I'm you know they have
humility well also she's following uh
Kaylee mcenany is that how you say her
name I don't really know who that is she
was the last white house president you
don't know who that is I she the goat I
sort of do she's the goat greatest White
House Press Secretary of all time she's
the best I had stopped paying close
attention by that she had all the
documents she would kill them she when
whenever she would get called out like
whenever there would be a question she'd
say that's interesting and then she'd
open the because you said this and your
paper said that and CNN said this and
and she would call them out on stuff and
she was just really really well
prepared very articulate she was
wonderful good for her we I mean that's
what it should be but she was operating
under President Trump you know so
obviously she's demonized it's just I
kind can't believe you don't know who
that is no I don't I know who it is but
I um it's just funny the she's the goat
well that's I had stopped watching all
briefings by then I used to go to the
briefing as a kid I used I mean I
literally would go there be in the
briefing room the former Kennedy
swimming pool and you and the first
thing you not I mean I was never a White
House reporter but I would was a
reporter so I would go to them
occasionally and the first thing you
notice is how impressed all the
correspondents are to work there I work
at the White House work the White House
got my my heart pass and then the
distance between that that little
credential they were so proud of and the
reality of their lives was like insane
like they're in this tiny little room
they're being treated with total
contempt by the White House staff who
thinks they're just [__] animals you
know it's like shut up they're eating
out of vending machines and this was a
different time right so like when I was
working as a journalist in Washington
like we went out to lunch every day at
like a good restaurant and charge it to
the company and like with your sources
like we had lunch every single day like
civilized people I don't even think that
exists in the world anymore where you
had time for lunch where you weren't
just so under the gun from your
corporate Masters you had to like get
back to work we we ate lunch and I
remember thinking these people don't eat
lunch they eat like a a stale Mounds bar
out of a vending machine like they bring
quarters to work so they can eat I
remember thinking your life like is
you're you're not even human you're just
like a little puppet or something and
but you're so impressed and like all
your neighbors know you know he he works
at the White House he's in the White
House Press Corps and the job like
wasn't even really a job you would just
like sit there and ask your question in
your little assigned seat like you're in
a high school
gym it was just awful and I just had no
respect for people who did that for a
living at all did you ever read it Fear
and Loathing on the campaign Trail come
on yeah yeah yeah it's amazing it's
amazing that guy uh gave sort of the be
that's I think probably the best window
into an outsider in the political
process at least in terms of the
campaign Trail it's the best window to
the press the best window to the
relationship that they had with the
politicians at least in the
1970s it's a it's an amazing book I was
talking to a campaign reporter I never
do that anymore but um I was this week
actually and he was telling me it's like
totally different like when I did it you
were all on a I mean it was bad actually
it was because it just cultivated group
think which was then leveraged by the by
the candidate for better coverage like
the whole thing was kind of an OP
actually but it was at least fun like
you were on a charter plane and like
you're flying with everybody and youd
hit three or four cities a day and like
their cocktails on the plane and you
know naughty behavior and like you know
they fed you and they kind of DED
everything for you it was it was it was
fun it was like a road trip right mhm
and now it's just like Grim they're all
driving alone and their little rental
cars to some obscure town in Iowa to sit
there with no access whatsoever to the
candidate write up their little reports
and then they get back to their hotel
and they're like writing up more for the
website and like it's just an a it's
such a bad job actually covering
politics that only the people who
couldn't make it in any other business
are doing it it's like the it's like a
reverse meritocracy it's only the most
kind of pathetic power worshippers would
ever do a job like that and um well like
critics yes that's exactly right most
critics want to be writers the most
they're like the worst people just as
people like well you've actually been in
show business so you have got better
experience with them or you have a lot
of experience with them but I've known a
lot of them who work for magazines or
newspapers that I work for and they're
the kind of people who have a lot of
cats and all the cats hate them you know
what I mean
they're just they're just like the
lowest they all have some like sort of
weird like wandering eye and they're fat
and they're like super into porn and
totally isolated from everybody I
actually
worked for for one of them for a while
who was a Critic for the New York
Post a guy called John P hearts and he
was he was one of the weirdest most
unhappy people I've ever met in my life
and he would come into my office
occasionally and he was rub his he had a
really hairy back and he would rub it
against the door frame this and like say
these kind of obscure he was stupid but
he didn't know that he was he was
actually kind of dumb but he didn't know
it and he would kind of philosophize I
was like 10 years younger and I was his
captive so he would just like lecture me
as he was rubbing against the door frame
and one time we went out to lunch and uh
we all had drinks of course this is like
mid90s he didn't really drink but he
ordered this drink with like a an
umbrella and and it had a water piece of
watermelon on the rim of the glass and
he took the watermelon ate it and then
he ate the Rind I'll never forget that
watching him eat the rind and thinking
of course this guy's a
Critic was his true love he was editing
this magazine but like his his real
interest was in writing about movies
and it was and they're just sad people
who did you ever read uh you know CIS
and Ebert did you ever read when uh CIS
Roger eert rather wrote wrote a he wrote
a screenplay no it's very bizarre it's
it's really sexual very strange it's
supposed to be terrible of course I've
read passages in it it's terrible but I
remember going
oh okay yeah they're not they're not
creative they're creative adjacent well
they don't have anything to contribute
that's what I'm saying they don't have
creative power right so
they're they probably could figure it
out if they had a different mindset I
think creativity is everybody it's just
a matter of how 100% it's in everybody
it just requires honesty yeah the
impediment to creativity is lying sure
and yeah I used to say that about joke
thieves that one of the real problems
with joke thieves is when they get
caught and then they have to write their
own material and the problem is they
don't understand the language they just
know how to say the sounds like if you
told me what to say in French I can't
speak French but if you told me what to
say and I practice it and I said it
right you would think wow that guy
[__] speaks French yes so that's what
comedy's like so if you got a guy who
knows how to repeat other people's jokes
but he doesn't know how to create them
see comedy is one of the rare things
where someone when when a like you get a
guy like uh Shane Gillis that guy writes
his own stuff he edits it it he thinks
it out in his head he performs it he
produces it he changes the order of
things I love that it's a complete
everybody does it pretty much the same
way there's a few guys that hire writers
and there's that's honorable there's
nothing wrong with hiring a writer and
it's also it gives jobs to other Comics
cuz some Comics are just really good
writers and they're not so good at
performing and so people will work on
stuff they'll collaborate on stuff like
Chris Rock would do this thing where he
would hire comics and they didn't write
the jokes for him but they would be like
guys who would bounce stuff off so he
would have his ideas he would go on
stage and then after his set they would
all meet and they would talk about the
set and you know guys would have
taglines like you could say this oh
great and they write that down they're
adding so it's a collaboration so you
have the the the master you have Chris
Rock who is so open-minded and
intelligent and humble that he brings in
other Masters and says tell me what I'm
doing wrong tell me what I could change
tell me what I can make better and they
work together and then there's people
that have people that are essentially
ghost riters they hire Comics to write
jokes for them they pretend they're
theirs and they don't really write them
at all so that's another level which is
to also anyone who does that get
successful I don't know I don't know I
don't not top shelf they get clo they do
well there's there's people that have
people right for them and they do well
but they're not the guy that everybody
goes to they're not David tell they're
not the guy that everybody goes to see
they're not the like David tell is the
guy the comics go to see when he's in
town yes like he just he's a master he's
you watch him he's Yoda you're like
Jesus Christ like how is he so good well
he's so good because he writes every day
because he's sitting with [__] a pack
of cigarettes and a cup of coffee every
morning writing things in a notebook and
he's practicing every day he goes on
stage constantly and he's just it's that
Japanese term Kaizen where you take this
one thing and just refine it to its
ultimate Mastery that's what he's doing
so these guys who pretend to be that and
steal jokes and then they get caught
then their material drops off a cliff
it's so obvious because frauds yeah also
because the very thing that allows you
to steal someone's jokes that's an ego
thing that's a like I want the laughs I
want to be the man or the woman I want
to be the [__] one up there showing
everybody ah look how amazing this
person is right look how amazing that's
the opposite mindset that's required for
creativity so creativity is not about
you creativity is about the ideas
creativity is about things creativity is
about how does this concept work with
these other Concepts how do I how do I
get it in the most digestible form if I
was an audience member what would be
like to feel this how what's the best
way to introduce it what's the way to
make it so that people don't think that
I'm being mean that I have a point or
that I've thought this through this is
not just a flippant thing like you're
allowing someone when you when someone's
on stage you're allowing that person
almost to think for you like you're like
take me on a ride like I I'll give you
my mind I'm not going to I'm not going
to be thinking I would do I'm not going
to I'm just going to let you think for
me if that person's not doing a good job
of that if it's clunky if it's shitty if
the the the transitions suck if the way
then it just interrupts this hypnos
hypnotism that you've put on me this
hypnosis it's it's a now I'm not let
inherently fraudulent yeah right I mean
I'm giving control of my mind over to
someone who is himself under the control
of somebody else
do you know what I mean mean if you're
stealing no if I'm in the audience right
and I would say this also goes for for
ideas for commentary you know that's not
funny but that's real right and you see
it a lot I've seen it a lot yeah you see
[__] a lot well the number of people
who are totally not controlled who are
really saying what they actually believe
with no weird agenda that they're not
telling you about is pretty small yeah
and I just have noticed that a lot
recently particularly on the question of
wokeness and Free Speech there are a lot
of people who are like on your side
because they're for free speech who
we're not actually for free speech at
all who are pushing uh you know a very
specific foreign policy agenda for
example and using another issue to lower
your defenses and let themselves into
your brain um and I think that's really
Sinister really really really Sinister
and it's becoming more obvious now like
if you're for free speech then you're
just for free spee because you support
the principle it doesn't the content of
the speech is is not that interesting to
you the fact that a sovereign human
being has the right to express himself
because he's not a slave he's a citizen
and a human being like that's what
matters yeah and if all of a sudden you
like become famous like I'm for free
speech and then you support silencing
people who articulate opinions you
disagree with like you're a fraud you're
kind of a Sinister fraud yeah yeah and I
that cuz that's the business I'm in I
boy I've really noticed that have you
noticed this yes and that's also the the
same kind of thing when you hear them
talk if you hear someone talk that's
saying something that's kind of
horseshit you it resonates with you that
that's you've you've seen you had a
moment with Barry Weiss on your show
that went everywhere I saw a clip of it
I never saw the show itself but she was
going on about she was posing as one
thing and then you pressed her like well
hold on a second what do you mean by
that you just attack somebody and she
had no idea what she was talking about
and it became really clear to me
watching that completely changed my view
of Barry Weiss forever I was like oh
this she's a fraud actually this
person's not honest at all like she has
a a very specific agenda that's all she
cares about the rest of the stuff is
just a is a kind of slight of hand
maneuver you're talking about the thing
with tulsy gabber that's correct yeah
she called her a to and she didn't know
what that meant well but she had no idea
like telsey gabard had straight outside
the lines on some Syria or something
uhuh um and and Barry Weiss was you know
going through the files in her head like
what does she have to
believe and she was aware that you know
tulsy Gabbert has somehow violated that
in a way that no one's willing to say
like in detail to fully articulate what
did Tulsa Gabbert do wrong no one will
tell you she's just bad yeah and then
what that revealed about Barry Weiss is
she's completely dishonest like she's a
liar actually you can't if by the way if
you attack somebody particularly
personally and can't explain why you're
attacking the person
like that's not acceptable you're a
dishonest person if you can't explain
why I think it's a common thing that
people do in private and they get
accustomed to speak like we're we're
talking like we're talking in private
we're just two people talking right so
people get accustomed to saying things
without being able to back them up you
know like oh he's a vaccine denier I've
done a ton of that in my life I as well
because I'm an [__] so it's like I
just don't like that person okay I have
as well but what I'm saying is I don't
know how much time Barry Weiss had spent
doing podcasts before that well she
spent a look I'm I'm just saying
like but I think important to be honest
about what your agenda is I think she is
honest I think she is honest and I
really like her I like talking her she's
a very intelligent against her
personally I just think that was a
mistake and I think you're allowed to do
that and hopefully learn from that and
don't do that anymore don't don't say a
thing that you and I've done that I've
done definitely done that I've said a
thing and I wasn't really exactly sure
what I was talking about my gosh I do
every day and I may have just done it
with Barry Weiss so let me be a lot more
specific about what I mean if your
agenda is neocon politics which is her
agenda just say so don't pretend to be a
defender of free speech as a principle
which is what she does how is she a
defender of neocon politics very wise
yeah like what what
specifically well anyone including me
and tulsy gabard who thinks that America
shouldn't be funding Wars that don't
help America she will attack um as as a
Traer to America or whatever whatever it
takes and so no no no that's her that's
her main interest which is fine and by
the way I actually have friends who I
disagree with really strongly on this
question who believe in neocon politics
doesn't mean they're terrible people or
I hate them or I'm not friends I'm still
friends with them but they're very
direct about it this is what I care
about okay fine you know I really care
about bird hunting and fly fishing and
or whatever I can and you don't that's
totally cool but be honest about it so
if your job is to defend the right of
free people to say what they really
believe then go ahead and defend it and
if somebody is not allowed to speak or
fired from his job for having an opinion
that you disagree with defend him anyway
I I just interviewed a guy who is a
black nationalist socialist okay so I'm
obviously not much of a black
nationalist I don't know if you're aware
of that but I'm not and I'm not a
socialist either but this guy is facing
prison time under the Biden doj because
he said things they don't like about
foreign policy and I just interviewed
the guy for an hour and it was like I'm
because on principle you should be able
to say what you think period what is
this gentleman's
name I he was actually a it turns out I
like loved him um oh and I'm embarrassed
I can't he's he's a member of a pretty
small black nationalist socialist group
it's like the Revolutionary black
nationalists or something like that
they're out of uh out of Southwest Flor
Florida and um he's literally facing
prison for repeating Russian
disinformation he's not even accused of
doing anything he's accused of saying
things that Biden doj doesn't like well
in a what were these things that he said
repeating Russian propaganda about about
the invasion of Ukraine and his point
was well there's a backstory here which
is that NATO has been moving Eastward
since
1991 and that's a massive threat to
Russia missiles on their border from a
hostile power is a threat and and the
bid Administration accelerated that and
in response Putin invaded eastern
Ukraine now you can disagree with that
but that's hardly a crackpot view by the
way I think it's actually true but even
if you don't agree that it's true that's
not you don't have to be a paid
propagandist of the from the Kremlin to
say that right I have said it I'm not a
paid propaganda is this a gentleman
that's him right there four Americans
from a black ower organization work with
Russian intelligence to spread
propaganda fed to spread propaganda now
propaganda
first of all you know there's a lot of
propaganda scroll up a little on that
Jamie so I can read what this is saying
it's covered up oh okay right guy that
guy right there okay subscribe real
quick yeah the people's Democratic Uhuru
movement in St
Petersburg so so he contacted he spoke
with someone in Russia they spoke with
people in Russia and then he no no no he
is being um he's charged with felonies
the FBI raided his house the first thing
they did was cover up the security
cameras and they went in there and
arrested they raided by the
FBI okay Russia's foreign intelligence
service allegedly weaponized our first
amendment rights freedoms russan to
divide Americans and interfere elections
in the US say Assistant Attorney General
Matthew Olsen now first of all
weaponized our first amendment rights no
your first your first amendment rights
are never a crime right they're
god-given
the government did not bestow them you
were born with them as a free person
period and the First Amendment simply
says you can't interfere with their
exercise that's it and in this they are
and and I looked at I I read this and I
thought and I reached out to this guy by
the way Matthew Olsen no I wish Matthew
olon would never do my show I mean the
guy whose salary I pay as a US citizen
no he would never speak to me listen
look at that that quote Russia's foreign
intelligence Services Alle allegedly
weaponized our first amendment rights
freedoms Russia Den its own citizens to
divide Americans and interfere in
elections in the United States that you
got to like why are you saying that say
what happened well but nothing but
nothing happened so that's the thing so
I'm reading this someone sent it to me
and I'm like okay clearly there's a
crime here like they were found with I
don't know mortar shells or they were I
mean usually the government makes up
they put kitty kitty porn on your
computer at least to discredit you
there's no underlying crime other than
they said something that the foreign
policy is establishment of the United
States disagrees with okay that's not a
crime by definition and this guy is
facing life in prison and it looks to me
cuz no one cuz Barry Weiss has not
defended him um I think this guy is
likely to spend the rest of his life in
prison and I'm like this is
crazy the rest of his life in prison yes
okay hold this is the thing he's I think
he's 83 yes how do you say his name
yella and three other US citizens Penny
Joanne hes Jesse Nel and August C Roma
Jr are charged with conspiracy to
defraud us hess uh oh okay you defraud
the United States uh hes yella and Nel
are also charged with impersonating
agents of a foreign government okay they
say to defraud the United States so
defraud suggests theft of something of
value right if I defraud you I steal
your money there's no allegation of that
at all and I actually read the charges
there's no the only allegation is they
said things that the US government the
bid Administration doesn't like that's
it and because they're unpopular and
they have views that are considered quot
quote sh
Fringe you know like crazy black
nationalists nobody wants to defend them
and my only point is not that I'm like
such a principled person this Al this
seems very obvious to me you can't allow
that you absolutely cannot allow that if
you believe in the first amendment in
the freedom of free people to say what
they think think so what this this
implication is they're saying that they
they were recruited um by the FSB so it
says uh prosecutor said ianov operated
an entity called the anti-globalization
movement of Russia that was used to
carry out its US influence efforts
overseen by the Russian intelligence
service known as FSB they recruited
us-based organizations to help sway
elections make it appear there was a
strong support in the US for Russia's
invasion of Ukraine and backed efforts
such as the 2015 United Nations petition
to decry the genocide of African people
in the US according to the
indictment back efforts what does that
mean look at that like it's negative to
back efforts to such as the 2015 United
Nations petition to decry the genocide
of African people but what just look at
that statement backed
efforts such as a thing to decry
genocide the United Nations Petition of
2015 to decry the genocide of African
people in the US according to the
indictment okay so the real
misinformation and propaganda is in the
charging documents actually the real
Liars here are the Biden doj officials
who did this and they're dangerous
they're criminals in my opinion but if
you read it carefully you will see that
the only crime is having opinions
that the people in charge didn't like
and were they in contact with people
from Russia yeah I think they went over
to Russia for some
conference so so they went over by way
but the way this typically works is they
say well you went to a country against
which we've imposed sanctions right and
you violated the sanctions regime in
some way like that's how they get you
they're not even alleging that they're
not even alleging that they're just
saying you said things that we don't
like that by the way a foreign
government we don't like agrees with
they learned those when they went over
to Russia learn it's all on the internet
they're they learned them I mean I guess
it doesn't matter where they learned
them I would because I've talked to the
guy and I've seen what they wrote the
opinions that they
expressed I don't you know the genocide
of African peoples in America I don't
even know what that means um I guess I
don't agree with that but their views on
Russia I generally agree with because I
think they're true and so does Jeff
Sachs and a lot of non-ra non-black
nationalists would probably agree with
the basic framework of their position
but whether we agree or not is not
relevant right all that matters is in a
free country which this was when I grew
up you have the right to any opinion you
want you do not have the right to hurt
people you don't have the right to steal
from them you don't have the right to
defraud people but you certainly
foremost have the right to any opinion
you want no matter what the people in
charge think of it in fact you have that
right as a bull workk against tyranny by
the people in charge like that's the
only thing that keeps this country free
is my right to have any opinion I want
and this guy is going to jail for his
opinions and you know I it's so crazy
that I kept thinking like is there
something that I'm missing like it does
seem a little Fringe this group I'd
never heard of them I'm not sending them
money okay um they must have done
something nope nothing and you should
see the video of the FBI right it's
unbelievable they sent they sent like
it's on the Internet it's on X I have
the video on there they sent like 40
armed agents with automatic weapons to
this guy's office and his house like no
exaggeration it was a full-blown like
we're arresting Al Chapo type thing for
this guy he's like an 83-year-old army
veteran it's
outrageous and I really find it
baffling that nobody who's like against
woke culture or whatever will touch it
and the reason they won't touch it is
because their foreign policy
views in general are more important to
them than their views on speech in the
First Amendment no views on America well
if you step out of line right so the
ideology is that we must support Ukraine
right so this is the Russia has a point
this is what they're saying so Russia
was very upset about the movement of the
weapons closer to their borders the the
the joining NATO all all the stuff that
was the hard red lines that Putin had
already set like if Russia Russia would
definitely do something if Ukraine join
NATO we all knew that so if you deviate
from that you're going to be in trouble
so better just ignore it because you
can't you you clearly if you look at who
these people are I mean these These are
people that would be supported by the
left whole wholeheartedly well they are
I mean it's like the Revolutionary
socialist yeah yeah they're not they're
not at CPAC this year but the left has
to ignore it because then 100% it
conflicts with this C left are just like
now they're actually ridiculous they
don't mean anything in fact we've moved
past the point where they don't mean
anything they do mean something they are
propaganda instruments designed to cloak
the truth from the rest of us that in
fact there's agreement not disagreement
at the center of power they all agree on
the things that matter and those are the
economy and foreign policy cuz that's
where the money is there's no effort to
say reign in the credit card
companies which if you really cared
about the country say but people really
suffering okay they don't have enough
money to live kids can't not only not
buy houses they can't afford rent and
why is that and one of the main reasons
is because they're paying like close to
20% interest on their credit cards
and okay we just imagine that in a free
market that's a good thing tell me why
that's a good thing who benefits from
that why are we for that again I'm not
for that I think I think the credit card
companies are
villains and they send credit cards to
kids at school and get them hooked on
this I think it's totally wrong and if
you said that in the US Congress people
would look at you like you had three
heads like what they just don't care
because there's they all agree that our
current economic system and our current
foreign policy assumptions are good so
that's not a two-party system that's a
one party system and it doesn't serve
the interest of the country and my
position is super simple the only
country country I have an emotional
attachment to as the United States
that's it I like lots of countries I
like almost all countries actually I've
been to a lot of them I like them all
but the only one I feel emotional about
is the United States because I live here
I was born here my kids are here it's my
country and most of the people in our
foreign policy conversation do not feel
that way so that distorts it really
dramatically and there also a lot of
them are are violence worshippers like
they get off on war they get off on
hurting people and on the power that
that um imbus them with and I think you
know the Liz
Cheney
model you know what I mean like someone
like Liz Cheney who's got like a really
sad and Barren personal
life a lot of them are this way weird
personal life failed personal life like
they don't have people who love them
they don't have kids who respect them
and so Adam kinzinger whatever they're
all kind of the same the more broken
they are inside the more focused they
are on like war and foreign policy
because it gives them a Feeling of of
power and strength and success like I
can't get my wife to respect me I can't
get my kids to listen to me I can't pass
any meaningful domestic agenda but what
I can do is Bomb the living [__] out of
a foreign
country and um there so there is this
it's not true for all of them but for a
lot of them there is this
syndrome uh that drives their behavior
but whatever the reason it's totally
disconnected from what's good for the
country and if you run America you have
one job
one job and that's improve America
period they don't see it that way and I
so I don't think the system can continue
because it's too distorted it's it's not
serving its original purpose at all so
what was it that these guys said that
made this raid possible they said Russia
and I don't want to speak for them like
I interview anyone who wants to see it
can interview and I just want to say
again like one of the cool things about
this moment that I did not anticipate
there's all this sad stuff happening I
know that you probably experience this
all the time is like finding not only
common ground with people you thought
you had nothing in common with at all
but also like liking them you know like
I actually liked the guy I'm sure we
disagree a million things probably mad
at white people I am a white person
whatever but like in my conversation I
was like I like this guy you know he's
honest and he's sincere he's principled
he was a veteran you know but whatever
no I really think what they said was
what I have said and a lot of people
have said um which is there was a reason
for this Invasion I personally think the
invasion was a bad idea didn't help
anybody I'm against War I'm sad the
war's ongoing but they were pushed to
this by a more powerful country which
would be the United States of
America with the threat of including
Ukraine in NATO it's really simple and
right before the invasion days before
the invasion they send poor Comm Harris
who has no idea what day it is to the
Munich security conference an area she
knows nothing about no experience in it
at all and they send her there for one
purpose which is to announce at a press
briefing with all the cameras rolling to
zinsky right there she says we want you
to join NATO what you no no other NATO
members were clamoring for Ukraine it
didn't even qualify for NATO membership
why would you say that when Clinton when
Putin's got troops masked on the
Ukrainian border you send your vice
president to the Munich security
conference with the world watching and
say this that no one even really wants
why would you do that to Prov War
obviously what's the other reason and it
was scripted like KLA Harris is not
freeballing stuff like she's saying what
she's told to say obviously it's not her
area she doesn't know anything about
this stuff she was told to say that but
why to provoke a war obviously so that
was my read I said that on Fox News not
a lot of people liked it but it just
seemed obvious to me I'm not making
excuses for Putin please uh I want to
protect the United States and I think
this war really hurts the United States
like my motives are always right out
there anyway I think they said a species
of that something like that and and the
last thing I'll say is that why was the
reaction so strong because it was true
they don't care if you lie no one in
power cares if you lie but a lot of
people are say they care when you tell
the truth a lot of people are saying
those things and they're not getting
he's like some black nationalist guy in
St Petersburg like who cares we can do
who's going to defend him nobody he's
some wacko he's some like 80 y old guy
who's like been in the like Fringe left
movement for the past 50 years you know
like new Huey Newton and stokeley
Carmichael he's like a relic of the past
and like he doesn't have a constituency
he doesn't care the modern democratic
party hates him he hates them and the
Republican party is like black
nationalism no thanks so he has no
constituency they're never going to like
you could say that and what are they
going to do to you you know nothing
because they're they can't but this guy
yeah crush him kill him and that's
exactly what they're doing and I really
think not to be like a' 70s liberal
about it if you let the weak get crushed
it's bad it's super bad you need to
protect the weak and this guy's
weak and so you think they're making
example out of him with this and they
can they have all this power this I just
don't understand why they would move so
many people why why they would get so
many agents why they would do this so
publicly for one guy's opinion or one
group of people's opinion well I don't
know I mean why did why did medieval
kings hang the heads of people they
executed from the gates right but it
feels like there should be more to it
like what what did they say so the the
problem is you're telling me I know the
problem is that I mean I'm just straw
I'm steel Manning this rather so the
problem is that they went over to Russia
and they talked with people in Russia
and then they're saying these things is
that the problem they're not charged
with that they're not charged with going
to Russia but you think that's the
motivation behind it because they they
went over there this a different article
uh has a quote from him okay yeah they
are not C at least when I interviewed
him they had not been charged with
taking money from Russia so it says
they've been accused of us they've
accused us of taking money from Russia
yesel said yesterday at a news
conference on July 29th we've never
taken any money from Russian government
but I'm not saying that because I'm
morally opposed to taking money from the
Russians or anyone else who wants to
support the struggles for black people
don't tell us we can't don't tell us
that we can't have friends that you
don't like he accused the UF government
US government of seeking to use the
apsp As It Pawn in its proxy war with
Russia the unsubstantiated allegation
that opponents of the war or
co-conspirators with a foreign power are
intended to bolster The Phantom of a
Russian Boogeyman in the public
Consciousness the escalating military
aggression by the us against Russia and
China is already being accompanied by
increasing oppression and an attempt to
criminalize left-wing opposition to the
unpopular
War well exactly so they're accusing him
of taking money from Russia they're not
they're not charging him so here's the
distinction which is like really really
important so there are two levels on
which the Department of Justice in all
administrations acts there's the level
of propaganda like what do we want
people to think and there's the level of
law what are we charging someone with
and you have to ignore the first and pay
very close attention to the second so we
have a legal system we have laws and you
can't actually go to jail unless you
violate one under the terms of our
system and so ignore what they're saying
about you Joe Rogan sucks he's a bad man
but in the end I'm busting you for
double parking and so really you're not
a bad man you're a double Parker under
the law and so if you look at the
charges against these guys they're
they're not charged with
violating sanctions
regulations they are charged with
totally Amorphis quote crimes like
defrauding the US government not for
money but for like defrauding it like I
guess counter signaling
it sending a message publicly that they
don't like I mean there's no crime look
it up except
speaking and I think that's a precedent
that we don't want to live with no no
doubt all right I'm G take a leak yeah
let's take a leak we'll be right back
we're gonna pee Tucker and I are gonna
pee
together yeah well that's the the
confronting of reality you're forced to
examine your beliefs and why you came to
those beliefs in the first place no that
is the beauty of this moment though it
is people are living uh intentionally
much more and it's also just much more
interesting it's not just you know it's
less shallow than it was for sure I
think so I think it's more nuanced
people have more Nu at least the people
that are paying attention have a more
nuanced perspective but then you have
the people that are in the Echo chambers
that are just digging their heels in
even more and you could spot them easily
because they well they're missing out
because there's nothing more liberating
than admitting you were wrong MH I mean
that is the that is like the moment of
Liberation right and that's the basis of
religion it's the basis of AA it's the
basis of anything that improves you as a
person is admitting honestly admitting
to other people not just to yourself
that like wow I got that wrong yeah and
then you're free cuz then you don't have
to hide it anymore right very important
and it's a beautiful thing and that is
like changing your mind I always notice
this covering politics that you know a
candidate would be like I've got him on
tape saying 10 years ago something
different and no one ever asked my
opinion but I always wanted to say why
don't you just why don't you say you're
absolutely right and the country's a lot
different from what it was 10 years ago
and so my opinions changed too like why
wouldn't they cuz I'm not a freaking
robot or a liar also I used to think
this because of that and now I realized
I was wrong exactly yeah which how great
is that I mean it's part of being a
human it's not being a flip-flopper it's
the best part of being a human well this
is an interesting time for that because
you see people that won't do that and
you could recognize them easily because
they're the first people to throw out
insults the first thing they do when
they describe you they'll describe you
in an insulting way and then they'll say
what they disagree with you about
they'll say something hard they try to
Define you they you're far right white
supremacist
racist yeah they throw it all at you and
then they say what you said it's so
funny I got called racist and white
supremacist so many times but when I
first was called that I mean it really
stung you know a lot because just of
where I grew up and how I grew up and
those are like the worst things you
could ever call somebody and um so I
actually like paused for a moment and
thought am I like I which I think it's
fair to ask yourself like am am I a wh
whatever that I've never figured out
what that was am I a racist not really
and I thought really the people I
dislike most are almost all white
liberals actually so you're racist
against white people no but like no I I
I am white my kids are white I'm not
against white people I like white people
but um no it's not that it's that so a
reporter once called me about this
you've been called racist like no
actually really just like you if I were
sort of narrow down my bigotries it's
like people like you I just think you're
disgusting
I really mean it too RAC racist okay all
right well it's a it's a thing you know
I don't think that works as much anymore
it doesn't work no well I think a lot of
the things that you overuse eventually
people realize like oh you're you're
you're yelling wolf again yeah well of
course and when people get hit with it
and don't disappear then it becomes
obvious that lacks power but it's also
you're trying to like use these words
Define someone especially someone like
you that has so many hours and hours of
talking about things like to to try this
reductionist perspective of someone to
reduce them to this ultimately very
negative thing and not say that they're
a human being and also the fact that
it's done by the people that want to
think of themselves as compassionate and
kind which is the most bizarre the the
left is so
aggressively
incompassion like they they're so
aggressively unkind with letting letting
people die of drug Odes on the sidewalk
that's compassion no it's not that whole
thing is [__] crazy well it's cruelty
actually it is and it's also when you
find do you know [__] Noz the yeah great
guy he opened my eyes to the
homelessness thing we had him on the
podcast and he was explaining how he was
in San Francisco and he was like what is
this is like they don't have any money
for this is that what it is like no
there's a whole business behind it
course and these people that are running
this homelessness initiative or whatever
the [__] they call it they're making
hundreds of thousands of dollars a year
some of them a quar million dollars a
year imagine making money off the
homeless and not doing a goddamn thing
but what's so funny is I I I do think
the root of their power and the one
thing they're good at is just charging
the moral High ground and taking it in
the first moments of the battle yeah
they just run up to the moral High
ground and like we've got this this is
ours and they'll protect that at all
costs and it's like that's kind of all
they have is this self-righteousness and
if you can puncture that it's like
you're getting rich from the homeless
actually yeah and is there anything more
disgusting than that it's some junkie
who's dying in misery outside the
convention center in San Francisco and
you're making money on that they're
essentially using those people as a
battery to expand the power of
government yeah their own personal
Advantage yeah they're they're expanding
government they're making more
government employees now there's tons of
people that are working on the
homelessness problem air quotes and uh
you know they probably all have blue
hair and they talk nonsense and
nothing's getting done and no one's
being punished for it but when they when
they did that study where they said that
that they had no data like how are
you what you you can't say whether or
not it's doing anything yeah you well
how'd you spend $24 billion but why are
they not treated as like the most
reprehensible people in our society I
think there's too many things to think
about I think most people unlike you and
I aren't even paying attention to it
they're paying attention to the fact
that the tents are are there they're
paying attention to if you go to Los
Angeles it's a [__] zombie apocalypse
but what they're not paying attention to
is what is going on how many people are
making money I didn't even know until
colon explained it to us I had no idea I
I thought it was just they don't have
any money they don't put any money in it
and they let these people sleep there oh
no no there's actual M all these
parasites yeah parasites government
parasites those are real of course and
you know this whole idea of I've created
so many jobs like what jobs are they
government jobs that are just [__]
cuz there a lot of those what's crazy to
me just having spent most of my life in
Washington is how close this is to the
lawmakers physically so the US capital
sits across from something called Union
Station which is a really beautiful
train station um right on Capital Hill
and so to get into the Capal you when
there's a massive homeless City there
people dying of drug Odes right there
and so to get to work every day
lawmakers have to like step over the
bodies of fellow Americans
dying like dying living Outdoors
[__] in the bushes addicted to drugs
which is Hell okay and they have to
ignore that on their way to creating
Utopia in some foreign country and
you're like does it ever occur to you
that that's disgusting that your primary
duty is to the drug addict your fellow
American you're doing nothing and you're
telling me how we're going to make
Eastern Europe into you know this Brave
New World
I don't know I just can't get past that
I think I'm not super sensitive or aware
or anything I'm not super anything
really I'm pretty ordinary but I think I
would notice I would I was like walking
into VOD in Ukraine Aid I'd be like [__]
there are like five junkies on the
street like maybe we should do something
for them no yeah yeah it's very bizarre
it's bizarre that they can rationalize
it or at least that they don't get
called out by all their people and this
idea that it's compassionate that you
have compassion to leave these people
and to give them Aid to help them and
give them clean needles but then you've
got to think like maybe there's
something bigger going on
actually because there's no yes there's
an entire sector of the economy now that
feeds off of human Misery the drug
treatment centers that don't work the
homeless Advocates who create more
homeless the you know migrant workers
you know American Born Aid agencies
workers who you know increase illegal
IMM ation and gang activity and all this
you know people are making money off
this the arms manufacturers that help
kill people in foreign countries etc etc
there's a viig and all of that it's a
scam it's a grift etc etc but like
there's something more like there are a
lot of people who seem to be just like
for evil for its own sake and you're
like maybe all the like crazy talk about
a spiritual war of like good and evil
maybe there's something to that maybe
that's not an illusion maybe that's like
everyone else has always thought that
there are certainly forces that have
evil consequences that exists but they
act on people from the out and you feel
it also on the other side I mean people
are better than they naturally are
sometimes like you feel compassion for
people or true empathy for someone or
you you really want to help someone
there's no advantage to you at all like
why are you doing that it's almost like
you're being acted on by good and all of
us have known those moments where we
just are cruel for the sake of it hurt
someone for the sake of it what's that
there's no advantage to us that's evil
acting on us and I think we're seeing it
at scale and like I grew up in the most
secular world you could ever grow up in
Southern California in the 70s and 80s
and in a very secular family and I've
never really paid much attention to that
and all of a sudden every not everyone a
lot of people I know who had similar
childhoods to mine similar life
experiences are like maybe there is like
a supernatural realm maybe there's more
than just like what we can see
and feel maybe life is more than just
ordering [__] on Amazon maybe there's
like a purpose maybe there is this
battle between good and
evil uh around us that we can't see but
that we do experience a lot it seems
like it's always been a narrative
throughout human history it's always
been this recognition Carls over there
snoring I don't have my headphones on so
I can hear
them you're snorting or snoring snoring
Carl snoring Carl the dog you oh Carl
the dog Carl the dog SN oh he's the best
but he snores when he sleep cuz he's a
little French
Bulldog he's a sporty little Bulldog
he's awesome yeah he's the best dogs
don't get cuter they might be as cute
but they don't get any cuter than Carl I
think that's right yeah I've got some
pretty good-looking dogs I will say yeah
I have a beautiful dog I have a golden
retriever but he's not as cute as Carl
Carl's a different thing don't tell him
that he knows he doesn't like Carl well
he he doesn't hate Carl but he like
ignores him he thinks of Carl as a thief
of attention only which he is yeah yeah
fair
so we've always human beings have always
at least believed that there are forces
of Good and Evil and that they they
that's what exorcisms are about right
the idea that you're possessed that
you're possessed by evil there's always
been this thought that there's good and
evil but when did you
start when did you start considering
that and thinking that that's cuz
weren't you at one point in time you
weren't you a a Grateful Dead head oh
yeah iisten listened to him this morning
yeah he used to travel around with them
yeah how old were you when that was
going
on um I went to my first dead show in
December of 1984 so I was 15 at speaking
of the San Francisco Civic Center yeah
the New Year's shows so they always
played in Oakland but one year they
played at the um in San Francisco
and so we were in Tahoe over Christmas
and for some reason my my dad was gone I
don't really know where so my brother
and I drove illegally from Tahoe in the
family vehicle to downtown San Francisco
how old was your brother 13 so you drove
or he drove I drove I drove 15 you drove
yeah wow Tahoe so was a couple hours and
uh I remember being on the freeway
like at 15 well we had a pretty
different of childhood um but anyway uh
anyway we did is that you yeah it's me
on the left get the [__] out of here
yeah I don't know you know I don't know
how that that picture is hanging in my
barn and I've never you know I don't
release any pictures of myself or family
or anything like that and somebody came
to my barn and took a picture of that
hanging next to my sink and um and put
it on the internet wow so that's my
brother Buckley on the right um that
picture was taken so my dad was a
reporter in San Francisco in the' 60s
and um pretty well-known reporter and
that was in the 80s when I was in school
and we were home for Christmas vacation
and he had covered the Grateful Dead he
knew the Grateful Dead my dad did so
they were uh in his office they like
came through DC and they like called him
and they came over to his off Jerry came
over to his office and my dad's like I
got Jerry garc here you guys should come
down so my brother and I we lived in
Georgetown and we had a vesa remember
those yeah and we drove our vesa was
freaking cold out I'll never forget that
we drove our vesa down to 6th and e or
whatever where my dad's office was and
there was Jerry I'd never met him before
he was missing the middle finger of his
right hand famously you know the famous
handprint grateful that handprint and
but when you shook his hand you could
feel his it collapse kind of because he
didn't have that middle finger but but
anyway so my brother and I drove to this
to the to the New Year show was actually
a couple nights before New Year's and we
didn't have tickets of course and um we
were in the park across
from there and we were you know whatever
doing the you know whatever things that
people do at Dead shows and we were
pretty freaking out of it and this guy
comes up out of nowhere and puts a
ticket around his face he goes here and
hands me a
ticket so my brother um was extremely
out of it I mean he was you know I never
should have done this but I was like all
right man I'm going in all right and I I
left my little brother in the park
during the show just like very very
impaired like super super impaired I it
was completely wrong to do something
like that but I did do it and then I
went in and saw the show kind of freaked
out in the middle of it hid in the men's
room for a while never forget that
standing on the the stall smoking
cigarettes is it acid trying to it was
no it was uh psilocybin mushrooms which
by the way I should just say I got sober
22 years ago I'm completely opposed to
anything like I don't take Adil like I'm
totally opposed to anything but um other
than nicotine and coffee but yeah it was
mushrooms so we ate way too many and um
started
to to uh to kind of melt down a little
bit but anyway the point is I get out of
the show this is pre selfa this is
1984 and I get out of the show and they
played actually a lot of tunes that they
didn't play they played Spoonful like
they didn't play Spoonful a lot it was
like a pretty obscure tune I'd never
heard it before actually and uh I
couldn't find my brother my little
brother and I'm like in charge and you
know my closest friend and lifelong
friends talked to him this morning and
uh but I couldn't find him and I was
like oh man my brother's gone but there
he was he appeared like an hour later he
had spent the entire show in somebody's
van there but he seemed undamaged and uh
it was great I mean not everything about
it is great I mean I do think the drug
thing got you know definitely hurt
people for sure but from my perspective
I went to a bunch probably 50 or more
shows and really enjoyed it and um I
love the fact that they had two drummers
that was a huge thing for me I love
Rhythm I think it's I think it's the
basis of music it's obviously the basis
of music I mean the instrument
instruments are are cool but they're
kind of like interior design and the the
architecture is rhythm and it's the
universal sound that every every culture
appreciates because it's it reflects
something that's pre-existing that's in
you everyone relates to Rhythm and I
just AB absolutely loved the drums and I
love they would always play like it was
called drums actually but they would
play a section of every show was just
drums um Bill cin and Mickey Hart just
going crazy on the drums and they had
drum circles and and I just like drums
to this day I listen to drums just just
percussion King Sunny ad day um the
Great West African drummer and uh anyway
whatever so yeah I like the Greatful
Dead a lot and still do and I like that
kind of
music jam music I like J music I like
acoustic music I love blueg grass love
blueg grass and Americana and to see
that grow to see Billy strings become
like a venue Packer you know like Billy
strings is like a big act right now I do
feel like creativity art has been
completely destroyed and eliminated in
the United States there's like you as we
were saying earlier you can't be
creative if you're not honest it's that
simple and we can't be honest so there's
no creativity and in the visual arts and
literature and architecture it's Di
but comedy is still alive thank heaven
and music for some reason has escaped
that and is still alive yeah and the
growth the explosion of acoustic
Bluegrass you know the banjo like one of
the great instruments ever um is just
thrilling and like a sign of life you
know at this late at this late stage
well I think when there's social
pressures and when society's in chaos
art does tend to thrive some kind of art
some art that's right comedy certainly
does now like comedy has never been
better amazing time it came close oh
yeah yeah the walls got breached whoa no
but a few a few years I don't know when
it was but you know eight years ago or
something it felt like oh wow you know
people can't tell jokes anymore we kept
doing it I noticed and yeah we kept
doing you kept the little little Embers
alive yeah well there was it was flames
it's just you you know when you get
people in a club and you take their
phones away and just have them just be
actual human beings and not be filming
everything just being completely trapped
with this idea of capturing something
and then putting it online then you get
to have a human experience you mean when
people like live in the present rather
than in the future far away that's one
of the great things about dat line going
to a good club that uses Yonder bags for
your phones is that it just takes you
out of like at the very least it's a
break like like this podcast is is a
break for 3 hours of phones there's no
I'm not no one's checking phones love
that that's very rare with human beings
where they can just sit down and just
have conversations for long periods of
time without being distracted by
something not in my house but yeah it's
a real problem with folks it's a huge
problem it's a huge problem and I the
one thing I will say about my very
unconventional childhood is there was a
huge premium on meals and like eating
with people
and spending 4 hours at the table was
like totally normal in the house that I
grew up in totally normal in fact it was
like daily and um that was our primary
form of entertainment and mode of
communication and you know thing that we
did for fulfillment and fun and I still
do that I still feel that way and we
have dinner parties constantly and there
are no phones and people talk and
entertain each other and it's like it's
so much more interest I'm not on social
media but if I were on social media I
don't think I would find that on
Instagram I'm just and I'm not attacking
Instagram but I don't think I would find
that anything like that no it's it's
it's definitely a lost thing and it's
such an easy thing it's such a fun thing
it is a fun thing yeah it's a great
thing and I think people enjoy it I
think that's also led to the rise of
podcast too because they don't they
don't get that in their real life so at
least they get to be a person who sits
in on these conversations I got to say
this is not being suck upy cuz I don't
suck up ever to anyone but the effect
that podcasts have had is just is just
incredible and I never would have
predicted that in million freaking years
I would have never thought it when when
I first started doing this it was in my
living room with my friend Brian and we
did it on a laptop and we had a webcam
and we were like with my friend Brian
yeah Brian redband of kill Tony you met
Bri yes I did I just no but I just love
the phrase with my friend Brian like
every bad story like my friend Brian we
were we were down in Mexicali and I just
me and my friend Brian we just started
[__] around online and then then we
started eventually bringing in guests
and then we eventually got a studio and
then eventually I got you know a big
place in La like a real warehouse and
then eventually moved to Texas it it all
just eventually happened but it's it was
not I mean I was in another part of
media for that whole period And if you
had asked me up until the last few years
like the future is clearly shorter
crisper more produced right right
everybody would have thought that
exactly everyone did think that
including me and I hated it you know I
hat it I like long form but I never I
was a long form magazine writer for
years so I I thought but I thought that
was over yeah not over everybody thought
that yeah even my friends they were
telling me how to edit my show they're
like you should edit that no one's going
to listen at 3 hours I'm like then don't
listen okay
do whatever you want I'm not I'm not
making any money doing this it was just
for fun I love that it was just fun for
years for years and years I did it just
with no money there was no money in it
forever what year like how many years in
did it start to pay for itself
five that's a long time yeah a long time
it was took a while I mean it was making
it was probably like sub
existing yeah but about 5 years in then
it started making money and then it was
like oh this is a business I remember
very clearly I was on stage Once in
Chicago I was doing the Chicago theater
and I had this story that I was going to
tell I'm like how many people listen to
the podcast and there's 3,700 people in
the place and they went nuts it was like
yeah and I was like
oh like I thought there was this like
thing that I'm doing where you know a
few people are paying attention I don't
even know what the I didn't even back
then I never even knew what the numbers
were I didn't I didn't even care just
well they may not have been like could
you even collect numbers accurately yeah
you can get downloads off of uh you know
like the whatever the uh provider was
that was um with the host you could get
like download numbers from the host and
they they would use that to inform ads
like oh he gets x amount of downloads
per month and then they would you know
that's when there's very few people
advertising on podcast all right let's
give it a try but it's one of the great
developments between
podcasting and Billy strings like I have
I'm serious I have hope that it's not
all going in the wrong direction CU you
can get this view that like everything
is falling apart late Rome yeah just a
matter of time before you know it really
does collapse and then you see these
signs that are not minor you know
they're significant that like no people
I mean I haven't met a person in the
past year who said you know I thought
this but then I was reading the New York
Times and I realized I was wrong like
not one person right but the number of
people say I was listening to this
podcast I was listening to Rogan and d d
it's like yeah really
noticeable yeah that's why it's
interesting it's it's it's interesting
because you could put people in front of
people and they might not even be right
they might be wrong but at least now
you're having conversations about
something you would never have a
conversation about before and even if
this person gets exposed as being
incorrect well now you have a more
nuanced understanding of what the
subject is about why people think
incorrect things and you know this idea
of like platforming people is a big one
today why would you platform that person
first of all platform is not a verb and
whenever they take a perfectly good noun
and turn it into a verb you know
something bad is a foot okay platform Oh
you mean letting an adult human being
talk right I think that's not only
allowed I think that's the law not only
that I think it's important for us it's
even important to talk to people that
are completely different than you that
don't agree with you at all well it's
especially important otherwise it's just
masturbatory it's it's interes it's just
you alone getting yourself off but it's
also interesting to know why these
people think the way they think and I
and also there's so many people that if
you talk to them online you'd have these
horrible conversations but if you sit
down with them as an actual human being
and treat them with respect and
consideration you talk to them like a
human being and you just try to be as
friendly and open possible as possible
despite what your differences might be
you realize most people have a lot in
common a lot more way more in common
than they don't but that's the secret
that they're trying to hide yeah so mind
control you know the end stage of Mind
Control is censorship right but it
begins long before that and it begins by
creating false categories that wall off
your willingness that prevent you from
wanting to know certain things or talk
to certain people and name calling is a
the most obvious tool like he's a crank
he's a racist he's a whatever fill it in
and then you're like I can't listen to
that person and I have to say your
willingness to platform or to have a
conversation with Alex
Jones I think was a revolutionary act
actually not that everything Alex Jones
says is right it's not not everything I
say is right or anyone says is right but
Alex Jones is an interesting person
and even if he's not interesting he has
been walled off from the rest of us yeah
through name calling and your
willingness to be like no actually we're
just going to listen Alex Jones and you
can decide for yourself well Alex has
been my friend for more than 20 years
well I well exactly
but even if he just the yeah but I'm
sure you have other friends you haven't
invited and just like you were not
allowed to talk to him and when you hear
Alex Jones talk you may not agree with
everything he says I don't know that I
do but you definitely understand why
they told you you couldn't listen to
Alex J well that's one of the reasons
why I had him as one of the first guests
when I came over to Spotify love that I
was like let's go what did they say well
a lot of people weren't happy we lost
sponsors it was it was an
issue um but I think it it did the the
job you know it it regardless of what he
said that's incorrect clearly the Sandy
Hook thing was incorrect you know Alex I
know Alex personally so I know what he
was going through and you know everybody
wants to talk about mental health and
they want to um praise people for being
honest about their mental health issues
and support them on their mental health
journey to Wellness Alex has gone
through some real issues and one of the
reasons why he's gone through some
issues is because that guy is uncovering
real [__] that's terrifying every
[__] day and he was drinking out of
control and you know he's just [__]
constantly stressed freaking out and
when you see so many lies and and so
much propaganda and and so many scops
that are being done on people you start
seeing them where they don't exist and
that's what he did well and he's also um
channeling some stuff there's you can't
call
911 in detail because you're super
informed before the fact he called it he
literally called it in the summer of
2001 he said planes will fly into the
World Trade Centers and they will blame
a man called Osama Bin Laden we know
that he said that cuz he he said it on
tape yeah multiple times and then he
said call the White House and tell them
this now let's just that's all we know
about Alex Jones let's just say that's
the fact set how'd that happen right how
did he do that no he's channeling
something that's super yeah of course
yeah there's like no other I mean tell
me how he did it otherwise I've asked
him about it how did you do that at
length he had dinner in my barn recently
we're talking about this how did you do
that I don't know it just came to me and
that's real that is real the super
superal is real and I don't know why
it's so hard for for the modern mind
guess cuz it's a materialist mind to
accept that but what you see and that's
not a new phenomenon that's happened
throughout history there were people
called prophets and there are people who
were prophets who weren't called
prophets but there are people who have
information or parts of information bits
of information visions of information
come to them and then they relay it it's
not from them they received it this is
like the you know one of the oldest
phenomenon in human in human history so
those people tend to
be a little crazy a little imbalanced a
little different from everybody else do
you know what I mean they live on Locust
and honey in the in the wilderness I
mean that's just like that's they're not
like everybody else and that's clearly
part of what I'm not saying that
everything that Alex Jones says is a
prophecy from God it's not but that was
prophetic there's and if it wasn't tell
me how it wasn't in in July of 2000 like
I lived in Washington in July of 2001
you know my dad worked in the government
like I was as well informed as anybody
could be about what was going on in the
government I've always been interested
in what's happening in other countries I
was aware of Assam Bin Laden I knew
about the Taliban I knew you know more
than most people there's not one person
who was saying not one person in
Washington DC was saying you know at
some point soon they may fly airplanes
into the World Trade Centers and blame
oam Bin Laden like that just wasn't a
thing so if you said that multiple times
on camera there 's a reason like and and
everyone I've said this to 50 people
what I just said to you and they all
look at me
like yeah that's stupid tell me how it's
stupid like tell me how he did that like
that's that's impossible actually he
didn't just do it with that either no
I'm aware he's done it with a lot of
things and that's one of the more
interesting things about him is that
like he he talks about Stu like he
talked about like I'm going to send this
to Jamie cuz this is one of the really
crazy ones that he he called and this is
like 2000 um 2000
probably I guess
2017 here it is let me find this give me
a second here I find because I I sent it
to him like how the [__] did you call
this because it's it's one of those ones
where you're like this is exactly what's
happening now
here it is here 2017 hold on a second
I'll send you this
Jamie come
on technology let's
go all right I sent it to you
Jamie so this is some guy's Instagram
clip that I found that took a clip from
the podcast and he's doing commentary
over put these on things on real quick
you got it yeah okay
cool here we go 22 years on podcast
Infowars Alex Jones and Joe Rogan
discuss what's currently happening right
now Google CERN technology vampires
aliens in a nutshell Alex was pretty on
point with this man message let me know
what your thoughts are is he crazy or is
he on to something it's really big so
okay um yeah pour another shot of that
get this out
proper all right let me give you my best
deep research Proclamation once you what
do you think is going but am I wrong to
still hold out hope that aliens are real
because I tell you as one the two guilty
pleasures that I still cling to is
Bigfoot and Aliens those are two Bigfoot
not so much I wish it was real but I
just don't are you ready yes Bigfoot
real no come on Daddy no are you ready
yes I'm going to give you the big out of
Joe there are aliens in this room right
now for real yeah you're not of this
world bro me you're the alien oh wow I
didn't know well here's what the elite
believe and let me be very clear asz the
media I'll take this out of context I
only go with what I can prove oh thank
you and people can't even handle that
there's armies we're fighting a
pedophile conspiracy but beyond that
it's a vampire conspiracy in that they
are interdimensionally sucking the
essence of our youth right and they
believe they're possessed by an offworld
entity they do yeah and Joe I've been on
air 22 years I don't get into aliens
metaphysical religion any of that I've
studied the elite and I've also
communicated with a lot of the top
people and and if you want to know I
will actually break down right now the
best knowledge right now what's
happening on the planet what's
happening the elite are all about
Transcendence and living forever and the
secrets of the universe and they want to
know all this are good some are bad some
are a mix but the good ones don't ever
want to organize the bad ones didn't
want to organize because they lost after
power powerful consciousnesses don't
want to dominate other people they want
to empower them so they don't tend to
get together until things are really
late in the game then they come together
Evil's always defeated because good is
so much stronger and we're on this
planet and Einstein's physics shut it
Max Plank's physics shut it all there's
at least 12 dimensions and now that's
why all the top scientists and
billionaires are coming out saying it's
a false hologram it is artificial the
computers are scanning it and finding
tension points where it's artificially
projected and gravity's bleeding in to
this universe that's what they call Dark
Matter so we're like a thought or a
dream that's a wisp in some computer
program some God's mind whatever they're
proving it all it's all coming out now
there's like this sub transmission Zone
below the third dimension that's just
turned over the most horrible things is
what it resonates to and it's trying to
get up into the Third di menion that's
just a basic level Consciousness to
launch into the next levels and our
species is already way up at the fifth
sixth Dimension consciously our best
people but there's this big war trying
to like basically destroy Humanity
because Humanity has Free Will and
there's a decision to which level we
want to go to we have free will so
Evil's allowed to come and contend not
just good and the elites
themselves believe they're racing using
human technology to try to take our back
minds and build some type of breakaway
civilization where they're going to
merge with machines transcend and break
away from the fail species that is man
which is kind of like a false
transmission because they're thinking
what they are is ugly and bad projecting
it onto themselves instead of believing
no it's a human test about building us
up and so Google was set up 18 19 years
ago this was I knew about this before it
was Declassified I'm just saying I've
good sources that they wanted to build a
giant artificial system and Google
believes that the the first artificial
intelligence will be a supercomputer
based on the neuron activities of the
hive mind of humanity with billions of
people wired into it with the internet
of things and so all of our thoughts go
into it and we're actually building a
computer that has real neurons in real
time that's also psychically connected
to us that are organic creatures so that
they will have current prediction Powers
future prediction Powers a true Crystal
Ball but the big secret is once you have
a crystal ball and know the future you
can add stimuli beforehand and make
decisions that control the future and so
then it's the end of Consciousness and
Free Will for individuals as we know and
a true 2.0 in a very bad way hi mind
Consciousness with an AI jacked into
everyone knowing our hopes and dreams
delivering it to us not in some PKD
wirehead system where we plug in and
give up on Consciousness because of
unlimited pleasure but because we were
already wired in and absorbed before we
knew it by giving over our conscious
to this system by our daily decisions
that it was able to manipulate and
control into a larger system there's now
a human Counterstrike taking place to
shut this off before it gets fully into
place and to block these systems and to
try to have an actual debate about where
Humanity goes and cut off the pedophiles
and psychic vampires that are control of
this AI system before humanity is
destroyed of AI how' they get how' the
pedophile is that it yeah it's pretty
much
[Laughter]
it it's incredible
it's I didn't understand about that was
seven years AG years ago yeah okay so no
seven years ago no one was thinking AI
was going to take over Civ you can see
why the FBI decided to destroy him which
it did um the people in I mean it's just
like what has happened to Alex Jones is
proof that at least some of what he's
saying is true because what why who is
Alex Jones a threat to did you see that
interview with the guy from FBI was
trying to hook up with that dude on a
date CIA yeah was it CIA that's right
and they they were talking about how
they can destroy a person yeah I think I
was mentioning in there too were you
yeah I was um yeah I mean there are a
couple okay so yeah again I don't the
third dimension I don't unknow anything
about Dimensions okay so I can't comment
on that but two things he said um are
true one um is that every civilization
every religion the Greek myths you know
every single one including Judaism
Christianity
Hinduism uh has believed that there
is sort
of that the spirit
world and Humanity are like that there's
you know they're hybrids yeah okay so
that's just a fact Genesis 6 um so you
know I don't think that's crazy at all
uh given that it has been the belief of
civilizations that had no contact with
each other I don't think it's crazy and
I also don't think it's crazy to cons
considerate I don't think we have a real
map of reality well we definitely don't
and I exact better put than I than I
explained that's exactly right we don't
have a real map and it's not crazy to
consider it and it was a very it was an
entirely conventional view up until
fairly recently um that yeah that this
the spirit world like I hate want don't
face breeds with people but that is that
everyone thought that okay right and
even the term spirit world is probably a
loaded term of course they're all Lo
terms how do you say it in a way that
doesn't sound crazy but the whole thing
sounds crazy because we don't
acknowledge the reality the actual
physical reality of the Supernatural and
it Israel that's the first thing the
second Point that's obviously true is
that people uh weak people which is a
synonym for bad people come together for
strength and safety they act as one the
hive mind is a is specific to a certain
group of people bad people and that good
people don't to come together but
they're coming together now and I just
not I just noticed this I mean people
independently who I know or sort of know
in many cases have long despised have
come to exactly the same conclusions
without talking to each other MH I know
that you have this experience all the
time yeah it's like I can't believe you
think that how did you wind up thinking
that right and not just on a specific
issue like foreign policy or covid or
whatever but like on a whole bunch of
different things they're all coming to
the same conclusion and they're coming
together and so that does
suggest you know uh big a big change and
a battle I mean it is a battle between
good and evil I'm not always convinced
I'm on the good side I've been you know
an instrument of evil many times in my
life and I'm ashamed of it but are you
talking about the Iraq War yeah the Iraq
War I've been cruel to people probably
even already on your show in ways that
are unjustified that's my instinct to do
that that's a fault not you know not
something to brag about it's something
ashamed of so I'm not I'm not saying I'm
always on the right side I certainly
have not always been on the right side
I've been on the wrong side many many
times but that doesn't change the fact
that there is good there is evil they
are at war with each other and we
are subject to the effects of that
conflict and that we're seeing it
suddenly play out in ways that are
really really obvious there's no
political explanation for the trans
phenomenon nobody benefits you can say I
hear these see these right Wingers be
like really it's all about the people
who make synthetic hormones they benit
yeah okay they benefit it's not driving
it that's stupid it's not about the
money actually there's no upside it's
not helping the kids at all if a child
has anorexia which is pretty common
actually in this country and the child
thinks she's fat you don't say to the
child yeah you're
fat you you don't do that you give the
child help if you can it's hard to treat
but you you try if a child comes to you
and says actually I think I was born in
the wrong body the last thing you do is
affirm that it's hurting the child like
why would you do that if you love the
child you wouldn't do that it's really
an EXC excise undertaken for the sake of
Destruction the sake of hurting someone
there's no real upside what's another
phrase description of that it's evil and
um you see that a lot a lot yeah and
um why like what is that what is it and
why is it so obvious to a completely
even a completely secular person like me
all of a sudden um there's a reason for
that we're watch you know history is
moving really really fast we're right in
the middle of it and I probably wouldn't
have chosen to be born at the time I was
I'd much rather sort of reach maturity
in 1955 really you know well I don't
know I don't get to choose you know I
don't like drama I don't like change
like I'm there was drama and change back
then there there was but it people
didn't rec well there was a cold war of
course there was a Korean War okay but
people didn't see it in their face right
in the way I don't think would you
rather know
but I don't have a choice I do know yeah
I'd rather know I'd rather be right now
yeah well you've got a much better
attitude than I I mean sometimes I just
my parents got divorced when I was
little and so I kind of like I don't
want change yeah I know to me I know
what you mean um you know um I was
having a conversation in the green room
with the club the other night about this
uh guy from Canada that's uh HIV
positive that's a
transom that's taking hormones so they
can breastfeed their 9-month-old
daughter so a biological male is taking
hormones and is now breastfeeding their
daughter off of their male tit and I
said if I was Satan if Satan was real I
would do that exactly if I was if
Satan's real I would I mean if Satan was
going to do something Insidious and and
unbelievably creepy he would do that
well I think he is doing that obviously
but this guy's a a real freak well but
right
using public money too but he's a victim
too I mean the thing about right because
the thing about evil the reason that
evil is distinct from everything else it
destroys the vessel it's held in the
conduit through which it flows destroys
the person so like that guy in the end
will not Thrive right he'll be destroyed
too and so that's how you know that it's
supernatural in other words if I you
know if I steal your iPhone and sell it
and I get an extra 400
like that's kind of explicable you
understand why I'm doing that I want the
400 bucks right but if I'm encouraging
your kid to castrate himself I'm not
really benefiting from that actually
there's no material benefit to me at all
there's no real psychic benefit it's
it's hurting for its own sake and um and
that's evil that's there's no political
category that explains that right and
then there's clearly money involved in
that too there is money of there's the
gender affirming clinics that have
popped up all over the country since
2007 you see the map of it's [__]
bananas but why would you want to do
that that's why would policy makers want
to do that why would anybody want to
make money that way right why would they
Cho to make Mone people it's the most
unnatural thing ever because parents
every parent at a certain age feels is
like I I like my kids I want grandkids
you want to protect your children to
continue yeah from bad decision so I
always think the politicians who push
trism on the country like their kids are
going trans too yeah they are right
they're not escaping it it's like
they're burning down their own house I
would like to see the statistic of
people in Hollywood like how many of
their kids turn trans versus the rest of
the world yeah I know some of them too
but how many of them versus the rest of
the world well a lot more a lot more
which is a a morally corrupt business
yes yeah like more than we knew more
than I knew you know the entertainment
business it's it's always been that way
you know Tarantino was talking to us
about um this famous old director that
had a a bedroom in his office where he
would bed the starlets and it was just
common knowledge that if you wanted to
be in his movie you had to [__] him and
you'd go into his office he had a
literal bedroom in his office we had
some of that in television yes I'm sure
yeah quite a bit yeah and I didn't I
didn't really understand I didn't you
know obviously partake in it or you
would know because all my text messages
went up in the New York Times so um I'm
not hiding any of my own behavior but I
mean I I will say if I'm being honest it
didn't really register with me I was
like yeah that's kind of wild and crazy
I just didn't you know like like my wife
I didn't want to blow up my family I
didn't do anything like that really but
I certainly saw a lot like a lot of it
like a lot and I just didn't really see
it as like horrifying I just saw it as
kind of like well you know creative
people are this way kind of thing but I
look back and I'm like it was really
dark well especially the producer thing
right that like the Weinstein thing that
the the way they ran the business that
that's how it was pay to play I worked
for Harvey Weinstein for a year did you
really yeah I did when 19 99 uh he had a
magazine um with Tina Brown called Talk
magazine I was the head political writer
for it and they had an office at carnegi
Towers in New York right below the park
and uh and I remember the big con I mean
I remember he was a pig I was not like
an intimate friend of his or whatever
but I certainly dealt with him and the
big controversy was he was smoking in
elevators and um that was and I've kind
of supported that if I'm being honest
but um but he was considered incredibly
insensitive and just like vulgar a pig
well he looks vulgar yeah well that was
certainly what everyone thought of him
where I worked Harvey's just a pig and
his brother Bob was a little bit less
that way he was also involved but um but
yeah people knew that he was a bad guy
but like but he made awesome
movies yeah and and also but he was just
powerful it's like hary Weinstein like I
want to [__] with hary Weinstein I mean
I didn't really think about it too much
to be completely honest that was just it
was just a guy I worked for but um I
don't know I didn't I certainly if you'd
played that Alex Jones clip for me in
1999 I would have been and I did see
Alex Jones Clips in 1999 and then in
later years where he was talking about
building seven and I was very offended I
was like outraged that he would be
suggesting that there was something
about 911 that wasn't above board that
there were you know things we didn't
know that were being hidden from us and
I was like mad at Alex Jones for saying
that I remember that really well how
dare you the building 7 one is wild well
it is W it is wild I mean I have no all
I know is 20
one I don't even know what year it is 23
years could it really be 23 years after
911 23 years later what's the
justification for classifying any
document around 911 there's no
justification well the same
justification of classifying the
documents about the Kennedy
assassination exactly 61 years later
yeah or releasing the covid vaccine data
75 years later of course yeah right I
mean it's of look secrecy is different
from privacy privacy is necessary for
the Dignity of this white you've got a
door in the bathroom and your bedroom
right you know you need privacy you need
private thoughts we have no privacy
whatsoever none no privacy at all thanks
to the to the iPhone and government
spying on us all so there's no privacy
but there's massive secrecy secrecy is
different secrecy of bets lying the only
reason to have secrecy is in order to do
something that you're ashamed of other
people knowing about that's that's
immoral and probably illegal and there's
more secrecy than ever and that means
that there's more lying than ever there
are more crimes being committed than
ever that's the shest sign of it why are
there a billion classified documents in
a So-Cal democracy because they're lying
to us that's why but 9911 like what is
the justification for
that I don't know the answer I really
don't know the answer but there is one
that's for sure yeah it's not methods
and sources you think it's methods and
sources trying to protect their Saudi
sources I don't think so you know the
wildest thing about Tower 7 is that if
you just say it looks like a controlled
demolition people get mad at you why
well I don't know because I'm not saying
that is a controlled demolition but I'm
saying if you watch it it looks like a
controlled demolition but that happens
all the time buildings Catch Fire and
they just implode in on themselves I
think happens every week right all these
poultry plants and manufacturing plants
that keep getting burned uh Through Fire
they all like it's the way it went down
yeah so I say why do they respond that
way and of course I responded that way
um so when I think looking back the
reason that I did was because because if
you call that into question you had to
ask a lot of other really obvious
questions you didn't want to deal with
and you might arrive at the conclusion
that a lot of your most basic
assumptions are false and that you've
been had and it's just too destabilizing
maybe right well the real problem with
Tower 7 is they go well okay if it was a
controled demolition how was that
engineered did they just decide to do
that before September 11th and you know
how long it would take to rig a building
like that right or was it built into the
building and how would they know would
even work and how would they do
something like that and how would there
not be a record of it being built into
the building like for someone to
engineer and where's the sound signature
on the on the tape there would be a
sound of the explosions going which is a
fair question yeah a lot of fair
questions and has there ever been a
building that experienced a tremendous
amount of damage because two enormous
skyscrapers fell right next to it
damaged it and then massive fire started
and then there's diesel generators that
are in the base so they have all this
fuel so they have this incredible
Inferno in the basement that weakens the
structure and is that why it collapsed
maybe to totally possible um a lot of
building Engineers disagree with that as
you know yeah and um they don't think
that could have happened uh in the way
you just described I'm agnostic on it
what I because I don't know the answer
and I have no way of knowing all I know
is that there's no justification for
keeping those documents secret that I
can think of and if there is tell tell
us what it is no one has bothered cuz
nobody presses and it's you know I'll
add that to the list of outrages yeah
you know what I mean and then it it
gives you this feeling of helplessness
because there's so many of those they
just pile on there's always another one
there government spied on me broke into
my phone and spied on me and I couldn't
get a straight answer to that and I'm
I'm not a felon and I'm well not only
that they used they got into your signal
account right yeah and then they leaked
it to the New York Times what they found
there so it's one thing to say okay we
picked up your text exchanges with a
foreign National which is
true um I text a lot of foreign
Nationals because of my job like why
wouldn't I and it's my right as far as
I'm concerned that's not illegal but we
picked up your text exchanges which I
think itself is a lie I think they were
targeting me I think they are now um I
know I'm pretty positive they are but
whatever leaving that aside we spied on
you we think we have justification is
there a justification for leaking the
contents of my private conversation to a
news outl in order to discredit me no
there's no that's secret police [__]
okay yeah I'm not whining I'm a victim
I'm certainly not a victim but what was
infuriating was my to and I got members
of Congress involved because I was
pissed and I felt
threatened I couldn't get a straight
answer they were just like we're not
answering those questions and what are
you going to do about it [__] what are
you g to do about
it you know I don't I don't possess a
drone Fleet there's nothing I can do
about it actually that's the truth so
when the system breaks down and things
like I don't know honesty
Justice the law none of those apply the
people in charge decide that doesn't
apply to me you are literally
powerless and um bizarre that the New
York Times wouldn't have an issue with
that well the New York Times does that
all the time but but but bizarre they
wouldn't have an issue with the
government tapping into your phone they
work for the government are you kidding
the New York Times yeah the New York
Times is a conduit for the lies of
government that's what it is it's their
tool and they're perfectly aware of that
I mean I used to write for the New York
Times as a freelancer I mean I've been
around the New York Times a lot and
there uh yeah there are a lot of really
smart people there for sure even now I
would less so now but there's still I
think smart people there there are I
know some and they know but they think
that that you know it's worth it because
they're bringing information I don't
know what they think actually but no
they're they're
tools of power and that's like the one
thing that you're not allowed to be even
if you think the power is good like
maybe they all support the agenda of the
US Government destabilizing the world
and impoverishing their own population
maybe they're on board with
that even if they are they shouldn't do
it because the job of the media the
Press is to keep power in check you are
kind of like the seat belt right you
know you make sure
that things don't go too far so um and
they're not doing that they're acting as
a willing handmaiden when do you think
that switched I think it's been the case
for a long time I mean if you look at
what happened to Richard Nixon which I
of course did not understand at all um
Richard Nixon was taken out by the FBI
and CIA and um with the help of Bob Bob
Woodward who was a Washington Post
reporter who had been a naval
intelligence officer working in the
White House working in the Nixon White
House and then he shows up like a year
later and he's this brand new reporter
never been a journalist at all he's a
naval Intel officer the famous Bob
Woodward we all
rever and he's at the Washington Post
and somehow he gets the biggest story in
the history of the Washington Post he's
the lead guy in that story well I I
worked at a newspaper I've been in the
news business my whole life that is not
how it works you don't take a kid like
his first day from a totally unrelated
business and put him on the biggest
story but he was he was that guy and who
is his main source for water date oh the
number two guy at the FBI
oh so you have the naval intelligence
officer working with the
FBI official to destroy the president
okay so that's a deep State coup what
else how would you describe that if that
happened in Guatemala what would you say
and yet the way it was framed in the way
that I accepted for decades was oh this
Intrepid reporter fought power no no no
this Intrepid reporter Bob Woodward was
a tool of power secret power which is
the most threatening kind to
bounce the single most popular president
in American History Richard Nixon from
office before the end of his term and
replace him with who oh Gerald Ford who
sat on the Warren Commission Now how did
Gerald Ford get to be Richard Nixon's
Vice President well because Carl Albert
the Democrat Speaker of the House told
him you must choose him we will only
confirm him when they sent the actual
elected vice president away for tax
evasion SPO agnu of Maryland
so you have a complete setup like an ABS
Gerald Ford the only unelected president
in American history actually sat on the
Warren Commission something else that I
accepted at face value until I looked at
it I was like that's completely insane
you didn't want to interview Jack Ruby
in your investigation of the
assassination okay you're fake yeah he
was on the warrant commission and so uh
sorry for the long story but the point
is like that that happened in front of
all of us but the way it was framed
cloaked the obvious reality of it the
people broke into the Watergate office
building from which the name is taken
Watergate was I think it was six of them
or seven of them all but one was a CIA
employee that that's real it's like look
it up on Google so the whole thing
Richard Nixon was elected by more votes
than any president in American history
in the 1972 election he was the most
popular by votes which is the only way
we can really measure popularity the
most popular
president in his election campaign and
two years later he's gone undone by a
naval Intel officer the number two guy
at the FBI and a bunch of CIA employees
you tell me what that is those are the
facts those are not disputed facts
that's not crackpot [__] that's just
look it up so why did they want to get
rid of
Nixon um you know there are a lot of
theories on that I mean we don't first
of all we don't need to know motive to
know what happened they meaning
unelected federal employees got rid of
Richard Nixon which is the most
anti-democratic way to make a leadership
change that there is okay I should just
say at the outet I actually kind of
believe in democracy obviously it's not
working well obviously it's ending
globally there will never be another
liberal democracy unfortunately but I'm
attached to it because I was born here I
really believe in it and it's better
than any other system so that's why I'm
pissed what was their
motive there are a lot of theories on
this there's an amazing convers ation on
tape um between Richard Nixon when he
was still president I think it was in
1973 and I think it was Richard Helms
the head of the CIA though I may have
[__] that up but it was the head of
the CIA I think it was Helms um and
Nixon says I know why they killed Jack
Kennedy so Nixon was a student of
History obviously a flawed and
complicated person but a very very smart
person and he was really interested in
why this guy who'd been president just
one president before him was murdered
and he didn't think it was a lone gunman
who was mysteriously assassinated two
days later by another lone gunman like
it's so obviously [__] and he knew
that and he said to say a director who
and you can listen to the tape that's on
the internet is totally silent on this
question so I think there was the
impression I don't think I know that
Nixon understood that the bureaucracy
was really in control of the country it
wasn't elected
officials and that's a massive threat
um because it's
true so and there may have been other
reasons too that I'm not privy to look
all I and by the way I didn't even know
any of this despite having moved to
Washington in high school and been
around this stuff a lot a lot a lot I
didn't know any of and I know Bob
Woodward personally so I didn't and I
Know Carl Bernstein personally I even
work for Carl Bernstein briefly so I I
knew some of the actual players in this
but I didn't connect the obvious dots
because they weren't framed that way
that's the point I'm making it's the way
that you frame things you can have all
the information available on Wikipedia
which is also controlled by the Intel
agencies but it there's still
information on there the information can
be out there in the public domain it's a
matter of seeing it for what it
is right
yeah so Nixon said that he knew why they
killed JFK MH did he elaborate
nope and it's worth listening to it's a
very weird conversation that takes place
in the oval
office which famously had tape recording
devices in it obviously this became a
big feature during the Watergate
hearings um but yes that conversation
and I may be mangling it slightly but
it's on the internet and absolutely
worth listening to and the CIA director
has this kind of sinister silence so
like if if I'm the president you're the
CIA director and I say I know why the
guy who is just president 10 years ago
was
killed the obvious answer would be like
well why right why why you what you know
why he was killed you've got insight
into the assassination of the US
president he doesn't say
anything is like a very weird response
like what just kind of throw that out
there like if you say to me you know
we're taking a leak you're at the next
Journal you're like I figured out the
secret to life and I'm like huh
okay that's like not a good response
right right right it's a telling
response did you hear Trump's take on
the JFK assassination why he didn't
release the files I know it
he said that if you knew what I know you
wouldn't tell people
either which is crazy well that's his
position on the UAP thing as well yeah
actually um and that's a lot of people's
position on it I mean you know Trump is
saying of course the CIA had knowledge
of it that is
known
um I
mean I mean the whole thing it's like
it's so funny there's so many levels and
there's so much I don't understand but
the whole JFK conspiracy industry and it
really is an industry more books written
on that than almost any historical topic
um is is filled with wackos right there
are a lot of wackos in there but it
obscures that fact obscures the larger
fact which is the facts themselves tell
an unbelievable story yeah and so um
whatever I could get into it at Great
length but yeah um yeah they they're
still classifying documents 61 years
later both Trump and Joe Biden have in
violation of my read of federal law kept
those documents secret there's no living
person connected to the Kennedy
assassination it was a couple
Generations ago there's no one person
who's whose secrets are being protected
it's an institution or maybe countries
there may have been countries involved
too I mean I don't know the answer but
there's clearly something worth
protecting and I know that when I I
spoke to someone who seen the documents
okay two years ago and I got um I got
one fact out of them which is yes the
CIA was involved and by CIA CIA is a
huge organization but James Jesus
Angleton the head of the operations
directorate had knowledge of this which
I think is well known but that that's
the view of someone who saw the
documents so I thought that was news so
I went on TV and said
that um the next day I'll never forget
it I went quail hunting and I was
driving back and I got a phone call from
Mike pompeo's lawyer Mike Pompeo was the
Secretary of State but before then he
was the director of the CIA and in that
position he plotted the murder of Julian
Assan so he is a criminal as far as I'm
concerned but um his lawyer called me
and said you know you should know that
anyone who tells you the contents of
classified documents has committed a
crime he's threatening me he in my car
I'll never with my dog sitting next to
I'll never forget this and I said are
you really saying that to reveal that
the US government had a role in the
murder of a democratically elected
president to say that out loud that's
the crime what about the actual crime
which is murdering a president like
you're covering up for that
Mike he had no no response at
all and so Mike Pompeo is the one who
pressed Trump to keep those documents
secret and so it's like what's crazy to
me is not just that Pompeo did that I
think Pompeo is a really Sinister person
and a and a criminal I think that I
think that because the facts suggest
that he was caught Yahoo news Mike
isakov wrote a long piece on this
several years ago his employees went to
Mike iskov and said hey Mike Pompeo is
plotting to murder Julian Assange who
has never even been charged with a crime
in the United States as CI director
that's illegal you're not allowed
federal employees are not allowed to
just kill people they don't like okay
just to set the Baseline here so
that's who Mike Pompeo is but he somehow
intimidated Trump into not releasing
this well okay that's all bad right I
think it's criminal Behavior what's
crazy is how Mike Pompeo is treated he's
treated as like a republican Puba in
good standing he fully expects to become
the secretary of defense in a trump
Administration which is like completely
insane why would you take a criminal and
give him nuclear weapons okay that's my
view I think it's a common sense View
and like he goes to fundraisers and
dinners and everyone's like hey Mike
Pompeo it's like no you're the guy who
kept information the public has a right
to no secret you're the guy who plotted
the murder of someone who committed no
crime you are the outlaw you are the bad
guy but no he's treated as like you know
like a pillar of Republican Washington I
think that's I think it's mindbending to
watch that and by the way you know
whatever that's all I'll say by the way
no I mean you know people don't say that
cuz they're worried getting punished
they're worried about someone putting
Kitty porn on their computer members of
Congress are terrified of the Intel
agencies I'm not guessing at that
they've told me that including people on
the Intel committee including people who
run the Intel committee the people whose
job it is to oversee and keep in line
these enormous secretive agencies whose
budgets we can't even know they're black
budgets they the parents the agencies
are the children they're afraid of the
AG gencies that's not compatible with
democracy democracy is a really simple
system even representative democracy
like ours the people rule they do so
through elections they express their
preference through voting they send
their people to the capital city to run
the government on their behalf whenever
you have unelected people who are not
accountable to anyone making the biggest
decisions you don't have a democracy you
have something else another system I
would call it a tyranny or whatever you
want to call it it's not a democracy so
that's like super obvious it's playing
out in front of everyone and no one
cares and no one does anything about it
and I and I think the reason is because
they're threatened and if you look at
the committee chairman who allow this
[__] to happen year after year they're
all and I don't know people say oh
they're compromised they're being
blackmailed whatever I don't have
evidence of that but I know them and
they all have things to hide I know that
for a fact and so it's not a stretch of
imagination to imagine that you know
some committee chairman who's allowing
warrantless spying on Amer Americans to
continue or whatever abuse they're
allowing knowing fully or hiding the
truth about uaps ignoring the UAP
disclosure Act of 2023 like why are they
doing that it's not impossible to
imagine that some guy with a drinking
problem or a weird sex life and that's
very common very common up there that's
why they're doing it because they don't
want to be exposed I don't I don't have
evidence of that I don't have proof of
that right but that that's not a crazy
thing to assume that that could be
happening and I said to somebody a very
powerful person
the other day in a conversation in my
kitchen an elected official holds a
really senior position a very famous
person I was going crazy I was so mad
about all this stuff and about the
warrantless spying and about the funding
for these insane Wars and I said to the
guy who serves in one of the legislative
bodies like got so mad my dogs were
afraid they're like well why you yelling
because I don't yell at home but I was
like all these people are controlled
they're all you know got weird sex lives
and all these things are hiding and
they're being blackmailed by the Intel
agencies and he said that I'm quoting I
know I was like are we okay so at this
point we're just sort of we're just sort
of admitting that's real like how why do
we allow that to continue the having
people compromise thing God that's an
old story it's the oldest story J G
Hoover I mean it's it's it's uh all of
them it's Epstein's Island it's
everything but look I don't have any I'm
telling you I'm What's The Phrase the
finance guys use open kimono like I'm
actually telling you all I know I don't
know anything else right um but I know
that the publicly available facts tell a
really clear story which is the
government is not acting on behalf of
the population and so it's inherently
illegitimate because its only legitimacy
derives from the citizenry the only
reason the government can do things that
it does kill people collect money by
force all the powers that it has come
from one place and that's the consent of
the government that's the only
legitimacy they have and that's where
it's fascinating this concept of Good
and Evil because when you think about it
if this is true and if these people are
compromised because they're secretly
perverts and creeps they are though and
they're corrupt and they they steal
money or they all these different things
are evil things lying controlling people
uh engaging in unnecessary Wars that are
going to cost thousands of lives for
profit all these things are evil things
so if evil is real evil would want those
kind of people to be in a position of
power yes and here's evil would want men
to breastfeed their children here's the
like op here's the here's the illusion
that we fall for time and again we
imagine that evil comes like fully
advertised as such like evil people look
like Anton Le
yeah you know what I mean black cloak
exactly sickle
evil is an independent force that exists
outside of people that acts upon people
I really believe that I've experienced
a lot and it's obvious and what vessel
do they choose the weak it's weak men
and women who are instruments of evil
the weaker the leader the more evil that
leader will be so it's and unfortunately
we've reached a time in American history
where every leader is either a woman or
a weak man pretty much and so there's
I'm sorry to say it that's just true and
the weaker the leader that's why Mike
Johnson everyone's like oh Mike
Johnson's such a nice guy well I know
Mike Johnson and he's perfectly nice guy
to the exent that he's like polite and
seems kind of Meek and restrained and
he's not saying [__] every ever
you know what I mean he's got like very
sort of button- down affect um but he's
he's a weak man and that's the man you
should be afraid of the people who you
shouldn't be less afraid of are the you
know headstrong loud don't care what
anybody thinks yeah those guys will go
off track but they're probably not going
to bet you know genocide or blow up the
world in a nuclear exchange because they
might they may be obnoxious but they
know who they are weak people just
become a host for evil you know uh an an
open empty building that evil occupies
possesses even um and that's exactly
what's happening to Mike Johnson it's
like absolutely crazy what Mike Johnson
is doing but it's not because he's evil
it's because he's weak and therefore
susceptible to evil it's a meaningful
distinction that I have noticed it is a
very strange thing how
many weak people wind up being leaders
in this society and particularly because
so many people don't want their live
exposed they don't want that eye of
Sauron gazing down upon them if they try
to run for president I get it or the
physical threat yeah physical I mean
look at what's happening to RFK where
the Biden Administration for the first
time ever denied him secrets service
protection it's absolutely as a
legitimate presidential candidate well
it's absolutely nuts yeah I mean how is
that I mean it's hard you know you
realize that a lot of the things that we
took for granted were actually voluntary
like people just didn't do things
because like that's just wrong that's
not fair you know what I mean that's bad
sportsmanship like there was a lot of
like self-restraint involved in running
a functional Society you can't kind of
in you can't just make an infinite
number of laws and enforce them that's
impossible you rely on people to just
not do bad [__] because like I'm not the
kind of person who does bad [__] mhm and
once the people in charge decide well
I'm just going to do whatever I want not
a lot you can do about it so the B
Administration denies him Secret Service
protection and you're like how can you
do that like well we're doing it what
are you going to do about it [__] and
like the answer is nothing actually what
is this most recent bill that they're
trying to pass uh about the ability to
monitor
phones well it's just the nightmare
scenario um it's something that they've
already capable of doing because they
did it to you and they did it through an
encrypted app oh they do oh yeah how do
they do it do you know how they use how
they got into your phone um well there
are two ways to do it's it's interesting
and I was I was with Ed Snowden um in
Moscow and talked a lot about this
because he's got the technical he's
first of all an excellent and principled
person and his his X feed is a really
good place to start for people to
understand what's Happening Here
um he's paid a huge price for being on
obviously for he's literally exiled to
Moscow um involuntarily but uh there are
a couple ways to do it um one you know
you could hack into signal I guess it's
open source um it was created with CIA
money as I'm sure you know I'm not sure
that's how you I don't think you need to
do that you just capture the phone
itself you just capture the phone and
the bottom line on digital security is
that nothing is safe from State actors
who want to spy on you period there's no
there's no electronic communication that
they can't monitor period what about
these things like Eric Prince has some
new phone out I think it's called
unplugged yeah Eric is a good friend of
mine and I've I I have a couple of those
phones and I've talked to him a lot
about it and he's a really a wonderful
person one of my favorite people
actually um but that that phone is is
designed for a different purpose I think
I know and that that phone is designed
to keep uh Apple and Google from
tracking you which is sort of a separate
category like um was this Jimmy this is
the bill I believe I think which Bill
the one you were talking about oh okay
house bill on
72 can we just roll down to what you
highlighted so this is like a perfect
example so um the Turner heims
Bill Congressman Mike Turner and Jim
heims so who are Mike Turner and Jim
heims so
it just be funny both those guys are the
most and who knows why and you can sort
of fill in the blank on motive I'm not
going to but those are two of the most
reliable water carriers for the Intel
agencies and for basically the federal
bureaucracy in the Congress like these
are not people who are working for their
constituents these are people who are
working for permanent Washington I would
say these are two of the most Sinister
people I know more about Turner than
heimes um but so it's not surprising
they're doing this it would permit
federal law enforcement to also Force
any other service provider with access
to Communications equipment to hand over
data anyone with access to a Wi-Fi
router server or even phone anyone from
a landlord to a laundromat will be
required to help the government spy so
that's the story right there so
basically warrantless of course
warrantless absolutely and in you know
violation of the Fourth Amendment to the
Constitution as if anyone cares anymore
no one does clearly but I just remember
when I was a kid and we're roughly the
same generation you remember this too
people be like oh East Germany like
there are more spies than there are
people East Germany was like the most
elaborate surveillance State ever
created and of course it collapsed but
we always make fun of East Germany or
North
Korea who do who has more privacy the
average North Korean or the average
American well obviously the average
North Korean because there's less
technology the US government spies on
its own population more than the North
Korean government spies on its that's
just a fact I'm not saying North Korea
is preferable I'm not moving there I'm
not carrying water for North Korea what
I'm doing is criticizing my government
because I live here because it was
better it can be better it should be
better and it only will be when we
demand it and it's not some [__]
esoteric like you have to be some crazy
civil liberties lawyer or something like
every person should demand just as a
starting point a baseline that no you
you're not allowed to spy on me I didn't
do do anything wrong right like what
right no privacy no Humanity you can't
be fully human without privacy and you
also have to take into consideration
that these people that are ahead of
these intelligence agencies that are
requesting these data are just they're
just human beings they're human beings
requesting data from other human beings
without going through a court without
going to a judge and getting a warrant
without stating a case without having
like some clear National Security
mandate something of course not and
there's no justification I mean by the
way we had fisa we've had the fisa the
foreign intelligence surveillance act
since I think 1977 so it predates 9/11
did it stop 911 oh I don't think it did
shut the [__] up you're not protecting
us actually you open the southern border
to anyone who wants to come you're not
checking IDs you're not doing any kind
of Biometrics you're not even screening
for covid so clearly you don't care
about my safety stop telling me you do
you don't you're a criminal stop this a
you don't care about my safety so using
my safety as a pretext for spying me is
not going to fly cuz I'm not that stupid
I may be kind of stupid I'm not that
stupid no you're doing this for one
simple reason because this is what
organizations do they protect themselves
they exist for their own benefit all
human organizations from the church bake
sale committee to the Department of
Justice they all are the same they're an
organism just like any other and an
organism's main goal is is to survive
and reproduce to get bigger and you just
see this throughout the federal
bureaucracy well just so happens that
the largest human organization in
history is the federal government of the
United States and so all of this stuff
benefits it it acrs to its own power
that's like like let's say you believed
every quote piece of science or
scientific Claim about global climate
change you would not reach the same
policy conclusions You' be like well the
first thing we need to do is Ban private
air travel because obviously that
doesn't make any sense and then the
second thing we need to do is you know
whatever you you'd look at it rationally
from a scientific if if you bought the
premise which I don't but if you did you
would that no you go through every
climate quote climate demand not one of
them disempowers large organizations
whether it's NOS or the government of
the United States not one of them they
all make the government more powerful
and they all make you less powerful so
that's when you know it's not really
about the temperature of the Earth's
atmosphere it's about making them more
powerful and disempowering you and it's
not about who runs those agencies the
bigger the agency the more effective it
will be in doing what all human
organizations do which is protect
themselves and increase their power it's
like that it's fundamental I guess
that's what I'm saying it's not about oh
elect Trump it'll change no it'll only
change when like we're just eliminating
the CIA and we're going to have like a
small Intel Gathering service that feeds
the president relevant information so we
can make inform foreign policy decisions
but we're not going to we're not going
to like overturn elections in other
countries in the name of democracy
because that's insane if we believe in
democracy then we're going to let people
vote for their own leaders because we
believe in democracy as a principle
right like you just get rid of all this
[__] because it's not helping us it's
only hurting us and um it would take
someone uh you know who'd be willing to
be assassinated to do anything like that
and so is is you're choosing your
leaders ask yourself does this person
mean it enough to die and that's the
same question you ask about your own dad
does he love me enough to die for me
about your own husband does he love me
enough to protect me from a home home
Invader at risk to himself like the the
basic prerequisite for leadership is
love of the people you lead and the
willingness to die for them and if you
don't have that you shouldn't be leading
period it's true in the military it's
true in business it's true in your home
and it's true in the government and so
no president will fix this unless he's
like literally willing to die for it and
short of that it can't be
fixed I could think of no better way to
end this conversation than that Joe
Rogan ladies and gentlemen nailed it
well listen man it's been very fun
getting to know you I think you are a uh
very you're you're a controversial
character in the world but you're
misunderstood and uh I think if people
pay attention to your actual work and
the things that you talk about I think
you're you're generally a force of good
I really believe that I feel like I'm
the most conventional person who's ever
lived yeah I don't think I'm radical at
all I'm the opposite in this crazy
time someone who's conventional and and
wise seems radical maybe I'm hoping for
a better time yeah I think a better
time's possible me too I do it's just uh
we're in for a rough
ride yeah I'm not I'm not disarming
anytime soon sorry yeah thank you Tucker
thanks Jeff bye everybody
ah
[Music]